<?xml version="1.0"?>
<root>
	<assets>
		<!--
		<item>
			<name>Interactive Reading for Toddlers and Preschoolers</name>
			<file_type>URL</file_type>
			<location>Resources\InteractiveLiteracyActivities\OnlineCourse\irtp\index.php</location>
			<url>http://www.evenstartnetwork.net/irtp/</url>
			<top_level_id>ILA</top_level_id>
			<second_level_id>OC</second_level_id>
			<tag>Shelley Gray</tag>
			<desc>Interactive Literacy for Toddlers and Preschoolers is a professional development course for  instructors wishing to provide students with a strong foundation for learning.  The material can also be useful in providing parents with the tools to interact with their children in ways that foster language skills and pre-reading skills.  This course is a combination of class lectures, demonstrations, homework assignments, and various reading resources focused on helping toddlers and preschoolers develop print awareness, vocabulary, oral language comprehension, and oral language production.  Shelley Gray is the instructor for the course.</desc>
			<synopsis>This course is broken down into 5 classes, each with videos, exercises, homework, and further reading.  Class 1 provides an introduction to Interactive Reading. In the first module of this class, Dr. Gray explains how interactive reading differs from typical book reading and gives examples of how teachers can plan for interactive reading with a toddler and a preschooler. In the second module, you will learn how interactive reading can impact children&#x2019;s development and where to look on the web for research on interactive reading, and in module 3, Dr. Gray explains the importance of reading different types of books to children. Classes 2 &amp; 3 both cover interactive reading with toddlers. Class 2 has 4 modules. In the first, Dr. Gray describes how families and teachers can set the stage for successful interactive reading with toddlers. In the second, Dr. Gray explains how parents and teachers can help a toddler focus attention during interactive reading. In module 3, Dr. Gray gives examples of what parents and teachers can say to a toddler when reading the book "First Words".  Finally, in module 4, Dr. Gray explains how to extend the book after the reading.</synopsis>
			<synopsis_cont>In module 1 of class 3, Dr. Gray describes how teachers can set the stage for successful interactive reading with toddlers.  This is followed by a module that lists the key activities that teachers can use when they read a book for the first time.  Classes 4 &amp; 5 discuss interactive reading with preschoolers. In class 4 Dr. Gray goes through the process of an interactive reading lesson when reading a book for the second time. Module 1 talks about preparing the reading. Here Dr. Gray explains how to select objectives, vocabulary and materials to prepare for a second reading. Module 2 explains how to introduce the book. The third module explains how prompts and questions during the second reading differ from the first and gives examples of each.  In module 4, Dr. Gray lists possible follow up questions after a second reading and explains how teachers and parents can extend the story to another context. Class 5 covers the same topics as class 3, only as applied to preschoolers rather than toddlers.</synopsis_cont>
		</item>
		-->
		<item>
			<name>Early Childhood Education Lesson 1: Mission Critical</name>
			<file_type>PDF</file_type>
			<location>Resources\EarlyChildhoodEducation\OnlineCourse\docs\L01_9_18_8.pdf</location>
			<url>http://www.evenstartnetwork.net/ECLessons/PDF/L01_9_18_8.pdf</url>
			<top_level_id>ECE</top_level_id>
			<second_level_id>OC</second_level_id>
			<tag>achievement gap</tag>
			<desc>This presentation discusses the achievement gap and how the encouragement of early literacy development can help overcome it.</desc>
			<synopsis>This presentation is the first of 7 lessons on early childhood education. It offers an overview of the achievement gap and the problems young children living in poverty face in their education. Pointers on using early literacy to help narrow the achievement gap are given. A section on brain development in young children closes the presentation.</synopsis>
			<synopsis_cont></synopsis_cont>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Early Childhood Education Lesson 2: Language and Literacy - the Link</name>
			<file_type>PDF</file_type>
			<location>Resources\EarlyChildhoodEducation\OnlineCourse\docs\L02_9_18_8.pdf</location>
			<url>http://www.evenstartnetwork.net/ECLessons/PDF/L02_9_18_8.pdf</url>
			<top_level_id>ECE</top_level_id>
			<second_level_id>OC</second_level_id>
			<tag></tag>
			<desc>This presentation describes how language ties into other aspects in a child's life, and how to encourage language use in the classroom.</desc>
			<synopsis>This presentation is the second of 7 lessons on early childhood education. It begins by discussing how language use is tied to other areas of a child's life, including behavior and environment. Then research is presented on the components of language, with some pointers on how to encourage language use in young children to help them succeed.</synopsis>
			<synopsis_cont></synopsis_cont>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Early Childhood Education Lesson 3: Building Family Literacy</name>
			<file_type>PDF</file_type>
			<location>Resources\EarlyChildhoodEducation\OnlineCourse\docs\L03_9_18_8.pdf</location>
			<url>http://www.evenstartnetwork.net/ECLessons/PDF/L03_9_18_8.pdf</url>
			<top_level_id>ECE</top_level_id>
			<second_level_id>OC</second_level_id>
			<tag></tag>
			<desc>This presentation defines the different pre-reading skills and how to develop those skills in the classroom.</desc>
			<synopsis>This presentation is the third of 7 lessons on early childhood education. The lesson starts by discussing the different aspects of pre-reading skills - phonological awareness, book awareness, vocabulary, and comprehension.  It then goes through 7 teaching strategies that will help develop children's early literacy skills.</synopsis>
			<synopsis_cont></synopsis_cont>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Early Childhood Education Lesson 4: Responsive Interaction</name>
			<file_type>PDF</file_type>
			<location>Resources\EarlyChildhoodEducation\OnlineCourse\docs\L04_9_22_8_2.pdf</location>
			<url>http://www.evenstartnetwork.net/ECLessons/PDF/L04_9_22_8.pdf</url>
			<top_level_id>ECE</top_level_id>
			<second_level_id>OC</second_level_id>
			<tag></tag>
			<desc>This presentation details how to use Responsive Interaction when reading with children.</desc>
			<synopsis>This presentation is the fourth of 7 lessons on early childhood education. It details how to use Responsive Interaction in the classroom to engage children and to encourage language use in young children. It also provides ideas for how to use RI in groups of different sizes, and how to evaluate if the interaction is working, both for child and teacher.</synopsis>
			<synopsis_cont></synopsis_cont>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Early Childhood Education Lesson 5: Scaffolding</name>
			<file_type>PDF</file_type>
			<location>Resources\EarlyChildhoodEducation\OnlineCourse\docs\L05 9-22-8_2.pdf</location>
			<url>http://www.evenstartnetwork.net/ECLessons/PDF/L05%209-22-8.pdf</url>
			<top_level_id>ECE</top_level_id>
			<second_level_id>OC</second_level_id>
			<tag>Scaffolding</tag>
			<desc>This presentation discusses how to use scaffolding to provide support to children and how to recognize developmental milestones based on the child's skill level rather than his or her age.</desc>
			<synopsis>This presentation is the fifth of 7 lessons on early childhood education. It begins by discussing the theory of scaffolding, in which adults, including teachers, provide positive social support to children to aid in the children's learning.  The lessons gives examples of how scaffolding can be incorporated into the classroom, then moves on to discussing developmental milestones.  These milestones allow teachers to ascertain where students are in their learning development, based on the toddler, preschool, and K-1 ready milestones, rather than on the child's age.</synopsis>
			<synopsis_cont></synopsis_cont>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Early Childhood Education Lesson 6: Dialogic Reading</name>
			<file_type>PDF</file_type>
			<location>Resources\EarlyChildhoodEducation\OnlineCourse\docs\L06_9_22_8_2.pdf</location>
			<url>http://www.evenstartnetwork.net/ECLessons/PDF/L06_9_22_8.pdf</url>
			<top_level_id>ECE</top_level_id>
			<second_level_id>OC</second_level_id>
			<tag></tag>
			<desc>This presentation describes the process of dialogic reading in which the adult interacts with both the text and the child while reading.</desc>
			<synopsis>This presentation is the sixth of 7 lessons on early childhood education. It describes how to engage in dialogic, or interactive, picture book reading with a child in order to achieve the most success in literacy learning. Dialogic reading involves having a conversation with the child, prompting him or her to talk about the text, and building on what the child says. Guidelines for doing this in the classroom are provided.</synopsis>
			<synopsis_cont></synopsis_cont>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Early Childhood Education Lesson 7: Play and Learn</name>
			<file_type>PDF</file_type>
			<location>Resources\EarlyChildhoodEducation\OnlineCourse\docs\L07_9_22_8_2.pdf</location>
			<url>http://www.evenstartnetwork.net/ECLessons/PDF/L07_9_22_8.pdf</url>
			<top_level_id>ECE</top_level_id>
			<second_level_id>OC</second_level_id>
			<tag>Play</tag>
			<desc>This lesson focuses on the importance of play in early learning and offers advice to preschool teachers on how to foster productive play in the classroom.</desc>
			<synopsis>This is the final lesson in a 7-lesson series on early childhood education.  This lesson focuses on the importance of play in early learning.  It offers examples of how preschool teachers can create environments and activities in the classroom that encourage the two types of play: constructive and socio-dramatic.</synopsis>
			<synopsis_cont></synopsis_cont>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>A Child Becomes a Reader: Birth to Preschool</name>
			<file_type>PDF</file_type>
			<location>Resources\EarlyChildhoodEducation\Guidelines\docs\NICHD_redr_brth_prk.pdf</location>
			<url>http://www.evenstartnetwork.net/pdf/early_child_education/NICHD_redr_brth_prK.pdf</url>
			<top_level_id>ECE</top_level_id>
			<second_level_id>G</second_level_id>
			<tag></tag>
			<desc>This text advises parents on how to help their children from birth to preschool develop early literacy skills at each developmental milestone.</desc>
			<synopsis>This document offers advice to parents for helping their children develop early literacy skills. It begins with a summary of research on how children learn to read and write.  It also provides examples of developmental milestones for different age groups, and advises parents on how to work on their children's literacy skills at home.  The booklet also tells parents what to look for in an effective day care center.  It concludes with a suggested reading and further resource list.</synopsis>
			<synopsis_cont></synopsis_cont>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>A Child Becomes a Reader: Kindergarten Through Grade 3</name>
			<file_type>PDF</file_type>
			<location>Resources\EarlyChildhoodEducation\Guidelines\docs\readingk-3.pdf</location>
			<url>http://www.evenstartnetwork.net/pdf/early_child_education/readingk-3.pdf</url>
			<top_level_id>ECE</top_level_id>
			<second_level_id>G</second_level_id>
			<tag></tag>
			<desc>This text advises parents on how to help their children from kindergarten to grade 3 develop early literacy skills at each developmental milestone.</desc>
			<synopsis>This booklet provides advice to parents of children who attend kindergarten through grade 3. It begins with a summary of research on how children learn to read and write.  It also provides examples of developmental milestones for different age groups, and advises parents on how to work on their children's literacy skills at home.  The booklet also tells parents what to look for in effective classrooms for each grade.  It concludes with a suggested reading and further resource list.</synopsis>
			<synopsis_cont></synopsis_cont>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Put Reading First: Preschool Through Grade 3</name>
			<file_type>PDF</file_type>
			<location>Resources\EarlyChildhoodEducation\Guidelines\docs\Put_Reading_First_Parent_br.pdf</location>
			<url>http://www.evenstartnetwork.net/pdf/early_child_education/Put_Reading_First_Parent_br.pdf</url>
			<top_level_id>ECE</top_level_id>
			<second_level_id>G</second_level_id>
			<tag></tag>
			<desc>This brochure advises parents on how to supplement what is going on in the classroom in order to help their children's early literacy skills develop through various stages of reading ability.</desc>
			<synopsis>This brochure advises parents on how to take what their children are learning in the classroom in regards to literacy and how to further that learning through interactions at home. This is broken down by the child's developmental level: children who are just beginning to learn to read, those who are beginning to read, and those who are reading.</synopsis>
			<synopsis_cont></synopsis_cont>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Teaching Our Youngest</name>
			<file_type>PDF</file_type>
			<location>Resources\EarlyChildhoodEducation\Guidelines\docs\Teaching_Our_Youngest.pdf</location>
			<url>http://www.evenstartnetwork.net/pdf/early_child_education/Teaching_Our_Youngest.pdf</url>
			<top_level_id>ECE</top_level_id>
			<second_level_id>G</second_level_id>
			<tag>assessment</tag>
			<desc>This paper provides suggestions to preschool teachers and child care providers on how to teach literacy skills to children from birth to age 5.</desc>
			<synopsis>This paper is aimed at preschool teachers and child care providers.  It provides suggestions on how to teach literacy skills such as: listening and speaking; the sounds of spoken language; print and book awareness; letters; background knowledge; and counting.  It also shows how to create an environment friendly to literacy development and how to productively read aloud to children.  Tips are also given on how to assess children's progress and how to effectively communicate with family members.</synopsis>
			<synopsis_cont></synopsis_cont>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Language Development Timeline</name>
			<file_type>PDF</file_type>
			<location>Resources\EarlyChildhoodEducation\Guidelines\docs\Mod 1 handout.pdf</location>
			<url>http://www.evenstartnetwork.net/pdf/Mod%201%20handout.pdf</url>
			<top_level_id>ECE</top_level_id>
			<second_level_id>G</second_level_id>
			<tag></tag>
			<desc>This timeline describes stages of a child's language development as he or she ages.</desc>
			<synopsis>The timeline is broken down into two categories within each age group: receptive and expressive.  The receptive category covers recognition of language and print while listening or reading. Expressive covers the child's use and initiation of language.  The age groups covered are: 1-2 years, 2-2.5 years, 2.5-3 years, 3-4 years, 4-5 years, and 5-6 years.</synopsis>
			<synopsis_cont></synopsis_cont>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Teaching Strategies</name>
			<file_type>PDF</file_type>
			<location>Resources\EarlyChildhoodEducation\Guidelines\docs\Module 2.pdf</location>
			<url>http://www.evenstartnetwork.net/pdf/Module%202.pdf</url>
			<top_level_id>ECE</top_level_id>
			<second_level_id>G</second_level_id>
			<tag>Scaffolding, ESL, ELL</tag>
			<desc>This presentation covers teaching strategies to help children develop literacy skills.</desc>
			<synopsis>This presentation covers several topics to inform preschool teachers.  First is scaffolding, a theory in which adults provide social support that aids in learning. The three domains of literacy development are then described: oral language, phonological awareness, and print knowledge.</synopsis>
			<synopsis_cont></synopsis_cont>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Assessment for Individualization</name>
			<file_type>PDF</file_type>
			<location>Resources\EarlyChildhoodEducation\Guidelines\docs\Module 4.pdf</location>
			<url>http://www.evenstartnetwork.net/pdf/Module%204.pdf</url>
			<top_level_id>ECE</top_level_id>
			<second_level_id>G</second_level_id>
			<tag>Assessment, ESL, ELL, culture</tag>
			<desc>This presentation describes how to assess children in order to inform instruction.</desc>
			<synopsis>The assessment discussed in this presentation is meant to tailor instruction to each child's needs and goals, not to identify possible special needs or to assess teacher or program effectiveness. The presentation provides questions to ask and activities to use in order to assess each child. Special consideration for ELLs is also given.</synopsis>
			<synopsis_cont></synopsis_cont>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Using Information from Assessment to Inform Instruction</name>
			<file_type>PDF</file_type>
			<location>Resources\EarlyChildhoodEducation\Guidelines\docs\Mod 4 handout1.pdf</location>
			<url>http://www.evenstartnetwork.net/pdf/Mod%204%20handout1.pdf</url>
			<top_level_id>ECE</top_level_id>
			<second_level_id>G</second_level_id>
			<tag>Douglas Powell, Assessment, ESL, ELL, culture</tag>
			<desc>This document put together by Douglas Powell presents research on assessing children in order to individualize instruction.</desc>
			<synopsis>Assessment is discussed here as a tool to ensure that each child receives instruction tailored to his or her needs. Questions to ask in order to assess the child are provided and special consideration is given to working with ELLs and avoiding cultural bias.  Ways to modify instructional activities in order to meet the child's needs are discussed as well.  Tips are also given for communicating with parents and caregivers regarding the child's progress.</synopsis>
			<synopsis_cont></synopsis_cont>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Assessment for Individualization Strategies</name>
			<file_type>PDF</file_type>
			<location>Resources\EarlyChildhoodEducation\Guidelines\docs\Mod 4 handout2.pdf</location>
			<url>http://www.evenstartnetwork.net/pdf/Mod%204%20handout2.pdf</url>
			<top_level_id>ECE</top_level_id>
			<second_level_id>TA</second_level_id>
			<tag>Assessment</tag>
			<desc>This worksheet provides examples of ways for teachers to modify instruction for each child based on his or her needs.</desc>
			<synopsis>This document presents a brief assessment anecdote of a child and then presents multiple activities teachers can use to modify their instruction to meet the needs of that child.  An activity for a group of staff to use when discussing that child's progress follows.</synopsis>
			<synopsis_cont></synopsis_cont>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Key Principles of Assessment</name>
			<file_type>PDF</file_type>
			<location>Resources\EarlyChildhoodEducation\Research\docs\Mod 4 handout3.pdf</location>
			<url>http://www.evenstartnetwork.net/pdf/Mod%204%20handout3.pdf</url>
			<top_level_id>ECE</top_level_id>
			<second_level_id>R</second_level_id>
			<tag>Assessment, ESL, , ELL, David B. Yaden, Jr.</tag>
			<desc>This document was put together by David B. Yaden, Jr. and presents tests and activities to use when assessing both native-speaking children and ELLs.</desc>
			<synopsis>This document first presents things that children should be able to identify or understand as they develop their language use.  It goes on to describe various tests that are available to assess a child's literacy development. There is also a separate section listing things to consider when assessing ELLs.</synopsis>
			<synopsis_cont></synopsis_cont>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>The Central Place of Language Development in Early Childhood Programs</name>
			<file_type>PDF</file_type>
			<location>Resources\EarlyChildhoodEducation\Research\docs\The Central Place Language Dev.pdf</location>
			<url>http://www.evenstartnetwork.net/pdf/The%20Central%20Place%20Language%20Dev.pdf</url>
			<top_level_id>ECE</top_level_id>
			<second_level_id>R</second_level_id>
			<tag>Catherine E. Snow, achievement gap</tag>
			<desc>This presentation by Catherine E. Snow discusses the results of a longitudinal study linking early literacy to 4th grade reading comprehension.</desc>
			<synopsis>Catherine Snow begins the presentation by linking early literacy development to the child's success as a 4th grade or even an 8th grade student.  She describes the results of the Home-School Study of Language and Literacy Development, which tried to decipher which facts at home and at preschool have the greatest impact on 4th grade reading comprehension. These indicators can then be used to inform preschool instruction with an eye to later student success.</synopsis>
			<synopsis_cont></synopsis_cont>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Oral Language Development Strategies in Parent Education and Parent-Child Time</name>
			<file_type>PDF</file_type>
			<location>Resources\ParentingEducation\Research\docs\CA Local Program.pdf</location>
			<url>http://www.evenstartnetwork.net/pdf/CA%20Local%20Program.pdf</url>
			<top_level_id>PE</top_level_id>
			<second_level_id>R</second_level_id>
			<tag>Gina Phi, Gloria Nudelman, California, achievement gap</tag>
			<desc>Two family literacy program directors present strategies program staff can use to educate parents on how to promote literacy with their children.</desc>
			<synopsis>The presentation begins by identifying the disadvantages children of low-income parents have when it comes to their literacy development. It then discusses ways that parenting education can be used to ensure that children are receiving support for their learning at home.  During parenting education class, specific techniques for working with their children must be taught.  It is then shown how these techniques are applied during parent-child time with support and feedback from the staff.</synopsis>
			<synopsis_cont></synopsis_cont>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Effective Collaboration for High-Quality Early Childhood Services</name>
			<file_type>PDF</file_type>
			<location>Resources\EarlyChildhoodEducation\Research\docs\NY Local Program.pdf</location>
			<url>http://www.evenstartnetwork.net/pdf/NY%20Local%20Program.pdf</url>
			<top_level_id>ECE</top_level_id>
			<second_level_id>R</second_level_id>
			<tag>New York, Mary Haust, Tonia Thompson-Grubham, Assessment, achievement gap, collaboration</tag>
			<desc>Two staff members from a family literacy program present research on how to make sure children of low-income parents are put on the path to success.</desc>
			<synopsis>The presentation starts with some statistics on the disadvantages children of low-income parents face and what factors can instead lead them to success. The importance of parent education is discussed, then some indicators of successful child care centers are presented. Specific ways to encourage literacy for different age groups are given.  A chart to assess the progress of 3- and 4-year old children throughout the course of the school year closes the presentation.</synopsis>
			<synopsis_cont></synopsis_cont>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Growing Successful Readers: Using Research as a Lens to Study a Language and Early Reading Program</name>
			<file_type>PDF</file_type>
			<location>Resources\EarlyChildhoodEducation\Research\docs\Vukelich_PPoint_12_06.pdf</location>
			<url>http://www.evenstartnetwork.net/pdf/Vukelich_PPoint_12_06.pdf</url>
			<top_level_id>ECE</top_level_id>
			<second_level_id>R</second_level_id>
			<tag>Carol Vukelich</tag>
			<desc>Carol Vukelich presents the components of literacy development and how to assess if a literacy program is teaching towards each component.</desc>
			<synopsis>Research is presented on the key concepts in early reading and how those concepts link to skills in the primary grades. Each concept is also given a learning trajectory that describes what children should be able to do as they progress within that concept. Methods for assessing whether a literacy program's activities meet each key concept and learning trajectory are given.</synopsis>
			<synopsis_cont></synopsis_cont>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Adult Literacy Development</name>
			<file_type>URL</file_type>
			<location>Resources\AdultEducation\OnlineCourse\website\index.html</location>
			<url>http://www.evenstartnetwork.net/LiteracyDevelopment/website/</url>
			<top_level_id>AE</top_level_id>
			<second_level_id>OC</second_level_id>
			<tag>ESL, ELL, Betsy Wong, John Nelson, culture, Michelle Ueland, Adriana Medina, Lynda Terrill</tag>
			<desc>This online professional development course discusses literacy development in adult English language learners. Videos from experts in the field, resources, links, vocabulary, frequently asked questions, and a final test are included.</desc>
			<synopsis>The first section of the course focuses on literacy.  It identifies three sections of native language proficiency and education, and gives suggestions on ESL literacy methodology.  The next section looks at how people from different cultural backgrounds communicate.  It also helps teachers deal effectively with students from different backgrounds.  In the module on phonological processing, you will learn various techniques that could help students recognize and manipulate the component sounds in words. The section on vocabulary development focuses on the complexity of word knowledge and gives suggestions for vocabulary recognition and development.  There is also a module on syntactic processing that provides various techniques that can help build learners' knowledge of grammar and syntax.  The final section deals with schema activation.  It gives suggestions about activating the correct schema, and presents various pre-reading strategies that aid in reading comprehension.</synopsis>
			<synopsis_cont></synopsis_cont>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Adult Learners: Teaching Strategies to Improve Learning and Comprehension</name>
			<file_type>PDF</file_type>
			<location>Resources\AdultEducation\Guidelines\docs\Adult_Learners.pdf</location>
			<url>http://www.evenstartnetwork.net/pdf/early_child_education/Adult_Learners.pdf</url>
			<top_level_id>AE</top_level_id>
			<second_level_id>G</second_level_id>
			<tag>Assessment</tag>
			<desc>This booklet explains the best research-based teaching strategies for adult learners.</desc>
			<synopsis>The first section of the booklet discusses five strategies for effective curriculum and instructional planning.  Assessment and testing are discussed in this part.  The second section focuses on eight teaching strategies to support enhanced learning outcomes.  These techniques can also be used by parents to support their children's learning.</synopsis>
			<synopsis_cont></synopsis_cont>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Research-Based Principles for Adult Basic Education Reading Instruction</name>
			<file_type>PDF</file_type>
			<location>Resources\AdultEducation\Research\docs\Adult_Education.pdf</location>
			<url>http://www.evenstartnetwork.net/pdf/early_child_education/Adult_Education.pdf</url>
			<top_level_id>AE</top_level_id>
			<second_level_id>R</second_level_id>
			<tag>Assessment</tag>
			<desc>This paper presents the results of a panel of experts who reviewed the current research base on Adult Basic Education in order to provide advice to educators.</desc>
			<synopsis>This paper presents principles and trends that can inform instruction of low-literacy adults who are no longer in secondary education programs. Principles and trends are given for each component of language learning, for the use of technology in instruction, and for the use of assessment and testing tools.  These principles should be taught together to ensure that adult learners receive comprehensive instruction.  The issue of ensuring that adults have a strong motivation to learn to read is also addressed.  Suggestions for further research are also included.</synopsis>
			<synopsis_cont></synopsis_cont>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Culture and Ethnicity in Social, Emotional and Academic Development</name>
			<file_type>PDF</file_type>
			<location>Resources\EarlyChildhoodEducation\Research\docs\Article02.pdf</location>
			<url>http://www.evenstartnetwork.net/pdf/Article02.pdf</url>
			<top_level_id>ECE</top_level_id>
			<second_level_id>R</second_level_id>
			<tag>Culture, Oscar A. Barbarin, minority education, achievement gap</tag>
			<desc>This paper by Oscar A. Barbarin describes the status of children
of color in the U.S. with respect to academic and
social functioning and summarizes what
is known about processes that constrain
and facilitate that development.
			</desc>
			<synopsis>Barbarin argues that academic success is affected in all children by socioeconomic, social, and cultural factors.  Children of color are often faced with social pressures and constraints that they must cope with that their white peers do not.  On top of this disadvantage, children of color are often provided with fewer resources to help them achieve academic success.  Barbarin discusses how early and sustained intervention in both a child's home and school environments can overcome these constraints and allow the child to succeed academically.</synopsis>
			<synopsis_cont></synopsis_cont>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>The Contribution of Parenting to Racial and Ethnic Gaps in School Readiness</name>
			<file_type>PDF</file_type>
			<location>Resources\ParentingEducation\Research\docs\Article03.pdf</location>
			<url>http://www.evenstartnetwork.net/pdf/Article03.pdf</url>
			<top_level_id>PE</top_level_id>
			<second_level_id>R</second_level_id>
			<tag>Culture, minority education, Jeanne Brooks-Gunn, Lisa B. Markman, achievement gap</tag>
			<desc>In this article the authors examine programs that serve minority families&#x2014;and find that home- and center-based programs with a parenting
component improve parental nurturance and discipline and thus their children's school readiness.
			</desc>
			<synopsis>The authors describe various parenting behaviors, such as nurturance, discipline, teaching, and
language use, and explain how researchers measure them. They note racial and ethnic variations
in several behaviors. When researchers measuring school readiness gaps control for parenting differences, the racial and ethnic gaps narrow by 25&#x2013;50 percent. The article surveys several types of parenting education programs to assess how they do with helping parents interact more positively with their children.  They found that center-based programs that work with parents and children can significantly reduce this gap in parenting and narrow the achievement gap between black and white children.
			</synopsis>
			<synopsis_cont></synopsis_cont>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Technology in Early Childhood Literacy Development: Family Literacy and Technology</name>
			<file_type>PDF</file_type>
			<location>Resources\EarlyChildhoodEducation\Research\docs\Article04.pdf</location>
			<url>http://www.evenstartnetwork.net/pdf/Article04.pdf</url>
			<top_level_id>ECE</top_level_id>
			<second_level_id>R</second_level_id>
			<tag>Regina G. Chatel, play</tag>
			<desc>This article by Regina G. Chatel discusses how children interact with technology and how technology should be integrated into the classroom.</desc>
			<synopsis>Chatel argues that technology should be integrated into the classroom because children are now exposed to it from a young age. Using natural home learning as a model, Chatel proposes ways for technology to become a meaningful part of instruction without replacing adult-child interaction.</synopsis>
			<synopsis_cont></synopsis_cont>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Family Literacy Nights&#x2026;and Other Home-School Connections</name>
			<file_type>PDF</file_type>
			<location>Resources\ParentingEducation\Research\docs\Article05.pdf</location>
			<url>http://www.evenstartnetwork.net/pdf/Article05.pdf</url>
			<top_level_id>PE</top_level_id>
			<second_level_id>R</second_level_id>
			<tag>ESL, ELL, culture, Michaela W. Colombo,  Massachusetts</tag>
			<desc>This article by Michaela W. Colombo describes the development of a parenting outreach program in Massachusetts meant to form stronger connections between the non-English-speaking families and the schools.</desc>
			<synopsis>The program profiled in this article was meant to further understanding between teachers and diverse families in the community.  Parents were taught more about the literacy practices used in the school and teachers learned more about the cultural differences among families.  The program targeted parents with children in preschool through grade 3.  It included community outreach, parent workshops, and in-house professional development.  A review of the program shows that low-income and culturally diverse students are more likely to be successful when a partnership is formed between home and school.</synopsis>
			<synopsis_cont></synopsis_cont>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Fostering Language and Literacy in Classrooms and Homes</name>
			<file_type>PDF</file_type>
			<location>Resources\EarlyChildhoodEducation\Research\docs\Article06.pdf</location>
			<url>http://www.evenstartnetwork.net/pdf/Article06.pdf</url>
			<top_level_id>ECE</top_level_id>
			<second_level_id>R</second_level_id>
			<tag>David K. Dickinson, Patton O. Tabors, achievement gap, Massachusetts</tag>
			<desc>This article discusses how early childhood programs can make a difference in children's success through working on the literacy skills of both parent and child.</desc>
			<synopsis>The article focuses on instruction in early childhood programs that furthers the development and use of oral language.  It also summarizes the authors' research on the Home-School Study of Language and Literacy Development, which followed children of low-income families from preschool to grade 7.  The study found that kindergarten test scores were predictive of scores in 4th and 7th grade.  They also found that a strong preschool program can compensate for a low-literacy home environment.  Three dimensions of experience during the preschool and kindergarten years that are related to later literacy success are: exposure to varied vocabulary; opportunities to be part of conversations that involve extended discourse; and home and school environments that are stimulating and promote literacy development.</synopsis>
			<synopsis_cont></synopsis_cont>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>The Connections Between Social-Emotional Development and Early Literacy</name>
			<file_type>PDF</file_type>
			<location>Resources\EarlyChildhoodEducation\Research\docs\Article07.pdf</location>
			<url>http://www.evenstartnetwork.net/pdf/Article07.pdf</url>
			<top_level_id>ECE</top_level_id>
			<second_level_id>R</second_level_id>
			<tag>Linda M. Espinosa, play, achievement gap</tag>
			<desc>This article by Linda M. Espinosa presents evidence that social-emotional development in the first year of life is the
foundation of language development and that social-emotional well-being continues to affect both language and literacy as the child matures.
			</desc>
			<synopsis>The purpose of this paper is to discuss the connection between early literacy and social-emotional development. First, early social-emotional development and its relationship to language development is discussed. Next is a discussion on the relationship between language and literacy. Third, the connections between play, language and literacy are presented.  Then there is a discussion on the early care and education contexts that foster early language and literacy and a section on how to foster relationships with low-income disadvantaged students.  The conclusion discusses implications for practice.</synopsis>
			<synopsis_cont></synopsis_cont>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Hispanic Parent Involvement in Early Childhood Programs</name>
			<file_type>PDF</file_type>
			<location>Resources\EarlyChildhoodEducation\Research\docs\Article08.pdf</location>
			<url>http://www.evenstartnetwork.net/pdf/Article08.pdf</url>
			<top_level_id>ECE</top_level_id>
			<second_level_id>R</second_level_id>
			<tag>Linda M. Espinosa, ESL, culture, ELL</tag>
			<desc>This article discusses how to get schools and teachers to better understand the Hispanic community so that Hispanic parents will become more actively involved in their children's education.</desc>
			<synopsis>Hispanic families are more likely to be uninvolved in their children's school.  These families are often low-income and their children are usually behind their peers academically. In order to correct this situation, Espinosa argues that educators must understand cultural factors that may be acting as barriers to Hispanic children's educational success and then devise approaches to help early childhood programs reach out to Hispanic parents and form partnerships with the home.  Espinosa then goes on to discuss these cultural differences and strategies that can help to bridge them.</synopsis>
			<synopsis_cont></synopsis_cont>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>What's Happening During the Parent-Child Interactive Literacy Component of Family Literacy Programs?</name>
			<file_type>PDF</file_type>
			<location>Resources\InteractiveLiteracyActivities\Research\docs\Article09.pdf</location>
			<url>http://www.evenstartnetwork.net/pdf/Article09.pdf</url>
			<top_level_id>ILA</top_level_id>
			<second_level_id>R</second_level_id>
			<tag>Elisabeth L. Grinder, Eugenio Longoria Saenz, Eunice N. Askov, Jale Aldemir, Pennsylvania, play</tag>
			<desc>This article presents an initial study of the interactive literacy component of family literacy programs and identifies high-quality practices for parent-child time.</desc>
			<synopsis>The purpose of the study reported on in this article was to assess the differences among interactive literacy components across different family literacy programs in Pennsylvania.  Program staff were interviewed in order to assess what they viewed the purpose of interactive literacy time to be, what information they use to plan this time and how they go about planning it, how they assess the success of the activity, and if they debrief the parents after the activity is complete.  The results show that staff often see the time as more of an opportunity for play rather than for literacy development and that there is little research that they can base their activity planning on.  The authors suggest strong collaborations with elementary schools and further study.</synopsis>
			<synopsis_cont></synopsis_cont>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Fathers with Low Literacy and Their Young Children</name>
			<file_type>PDF</file_type>
			<location>Resources\EarlyChildhoodEducation\Research\docs\Article10.pdf</location>
			<url>http://www.evenstartnetwork.net/pdf/Article10.pdf</url>
			<top_level_id>ECE</top_level_id>
			<second_level_id>R</second_level_id>
			<tag>Diane Karther, West Virginia</tag>
			<desc>This article presents the attitudes and expectations of low-literacy, low-income fathers in West Virginia toward their own and their children's academic achievement.</desc>
			<synopsis>For the study the researchers interviewed fathers participating in family literacy programs.  Though the wives and children were more directly involved in the program, over time the fathers increased book use and reading time with their children.  The interest they show in their children's education even though they themselves have struggled academically shows that instructors should make an effort to include both parents in the child's instruction.  Higher levels of male staff in family literacy programs may also encourage more participation by the fathers.</synopsis>
			<synopsis_cont></synopsis_cont>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Getting Ready to Read: Emergent Literacy and Family Literacy</name>
			<file_type>PDF</file_type>
			<location>Resources\EarlyChildhoodEducation\Research\docs\Article11.pdf</location>
			<url>http://www.evenstartnetwork.net/pdf/Article11.pdf</url>
			<top_level_id>ECE</top_level_id>
			<second_level_id>R</second_level_id>
			<tag>Christopher J. Lonigan, Grover J. Whitehurst, achievement gap</tag>
			<desc>This article discusses recent research in early literacy development.</desc>
			<synopsis>The research examined in this paper indicates that there are several methods that may be used to make a significant impact on the emerging literacy skills of young children.  The latest research on all components of literacy development is surveyed, as well as research on environments that facilitate children obtaining those skills.  The relationship between socioeconomic status and academic achievement is also discussed.  The policy implications of this research for family literacy programs and suggestions for best practices in those programs conclude the paper.</synopsis>
			<synopsis_cont></synopsis_cont>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Books Make a Difference: A Study of Access to Literacy</name>
			<file_type>PDF</file_type>
			<location>Resources\EarlyChildhoodEducation\Research\docs\Article12.pdf</location>
			<url>http://www.evenstartnetwork.net/pdf/Article12.pdf</url>
			<top_level_id>ECE</top_level_id>
			<second_level_id>R</second_level_id>
			<tag>Susan B. Neuman, achievement gap, Pennsylvania</tag>
			<desc>This article by Susan B. Neuman details a study that gave books to child care centers to see if increased access to books improved children's literacy.</desc>
			<synopsis>The study summarized in the article gave books to child care centers servicing economically disadvantaged children in a ratio of 5 books per child. Training in literacy instruction was also provided to the caregivers.  The children were tested before and after the school year in which the books were given, and the children with access to books performed significantly better on the post-test than the control group who did not receive books. The study illustrates the disadvantage that low-income communities that do not provide enough books to their children have.</synopsis>
			<synopsis_cont></synopsis_cont>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Stories, Coupons, and the TV Guide: Relationships Between Home Literacy Experiences and Emergent Literacy Knowledge</name>
			<file_type>PDF</file_type>
			<location>Resources\EarlyChildhoodEducation\Research\docs\Article13.pdf</location>
			<url>http://www.evenstartnetwork.net/pdf/Article13.pdf</url>
			<top_level_id>ECE</top_level_id>
			<second_level_id>R</second_level_id>
			<tag>Victoria Purcell-Gates, achievement gap</tag>
			<desc>This article summarizes the results of a descriptive study that logged the literacy practices in 20 homes and correlated those with the children's literacy abilities.</desc>
			<synopsis>This study observed the range, frequency, and complexity of literacy practices in low-income homes as well as the emergent literacy level of the children in the household.  From the varied practices across families, the results show that (a) children&#x2019;s understanding of the intentionality of print is related to both the frequency of literacy events in the home and to their personal focus and involvement in the literacy events, (b) children knew more about the alphabetic principle and the specific forms of written language more in homes
where literate members read and wrote at more complex levels of discourse for their own entertainment and leisure, and (c) parents&#x2019; intentional involvement in their children&#x2019;s literacy learning was higher when their children began formal literacy instruction in school. Reflections on literacy as cultural practice and the ways in which
school and home learning can build upon each other are also discussed.
			</synopsis>
			<synopsis_cont></synopsis_cont>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Fast Start: A Promising Practice for Family Literacy Programs</name>
			<file_type>PDF</file_type>
			<location>Resources\InteractiveLiteracyActivities\Research\docs\Article14.pdf</location>
			<url>http://www.evenstartnetwork.net/pdf/Article14.pdf</url>
			<top_level_id>ILA</top_level_id>
			<second_level_id>R</second_level_id>
			<tag>Nancy Padak, Tim Rasinski, Ohio</tag>
			<desc>This article describes a parent-child literacy involvement program called Fast Start that is successful in using research-based practices to further literacy skills.</desc>
			<synopsis>The Fast Start program described here is an at-home parent-child literacy program that aims to keep parents actively involved in their children's education without families feeling burdened by time or resource constraints.  The article states the principles behind the way the program works and how those principles can be applied to other literacy programs.  Sample lessons that staff can use with families are given.</synopsis>
			<synopsis_cont></synopsis_cont>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Learning to Read the World: Literacy in the First 3 Years</name>
			<file_type>PDF</file_type>
			<location>Resources\InteractiveLiteracyActivities\Research\docs\Article15.pdf</location>
			<url>http://www.evenstartnetwork.net/pdf/Article15.pdf</url>
			<top_level_id>ILA</top_level_id>
			<second_level_id>R</second_level_id>
			<tag>Sharon E. Rosenkoetter, Joanne Knapp-Philo, culture</tag>
			<desc>This article describes the importance of literacy development in young children and the ways that it can be promoted.</desc>
			<synopsis>This article argues that a child's experience from birth to 3 years sets the stage for his or her later academic success.  It also argues that everyone can influence a young child positively.  A section is given to describing how different categories of people can influence a child's literacy development: families, caregivers, family literacy program staff, and the surrounding community.</synopsis>
			<synopsis_cont></synopsis_cont>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Parental Involvement in the Development of Children's Reading Skill: A Five-Year Longitudinal Study</name>
			<file_type>PDF</file_type>
			<location>Resources\InteractiveLiteracyActivities\Research\docs\Article16.pdf</location>
			<url>http://www.evenstartnetwork.net/pdf/Article16.pdf</url>
			<top_level_id>ILA</top_level_id>
			<second_level_id>R</second_level_id>
			<tag>Monique Senechal, Jo-Anne LeFevre</tag>
			<desc>This article presents the findings of a 5-year longitudinal study of middle- and upper-middle class children in which the relationships among early home literacy experiences, subsequent language and emergent literacy skills, and later reading achievement were examined.</desc>
			<synopsis>The study results showed that children's exposure to books was related to the development of vocabulary and listening comprehension skills, and that parent involvement in teaching children about reading and writing was related to the development of early literacy skills.  Early literacy skills directly predicted word reading at the end of grade 1 and indirectly predicted reading in grade 3, and word reading in grade 1 predicted reading comprehension in grade 3.  The article concludes with the idea that the various pathways that lead to fluent reading have their roots in different aspects of children's early experiences.</synopsis>
			<synopsis_cont></synopsis_cont>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>The Role of Literacy in Early Childhood Education</name>
			<file_type>PDF</file_type>
			<location>Resources\EarlyChildhoodEducation\Research\docs\Article17.pdf</location>
			<url>http://www.evenstartnetwork.net/pdf/Article17.pdf</url>
			<top_level_id>ECE</top_level_id>
			<second_level_id>R</second_level_id>
			<tag>Dorothy S. Strickland</tag>
			<desc>This article by Dorothy Strickland presents some
considerations for planning the content and implementation of successful early childhood parent education programs.
			</desc>
			<synopsis>The article starts with the thesis that learning to read is an ongoing process that begins at a very young age.  Tips for parents and educators are presented for developing both oral language and literacy skills in young children.  Strickland also suggests involving parents in the literacy program as much as possible, and making each literacy activity specific and practical.  She says that parent education programs should also ideally be offered in conjunction with other services in order to make them accessible to the largest number of families.</synopsis>
			<synopsis_cont></synopsis_cont>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>The Role of Parents and Grandparents in Children's Cognitive Development: Focus on Language and Literacy</name>
			<file_type>PDF</file_type>
			<location>Resources\InteractiveLiteracyActivities\Research\docs\Article18.pdf</location>
			<url>http://www.evenstartnetwork.net/pdf/Article18.pdf</url>
			<top_level_id>ILA</top_level_id>
			<second_level_id>G</second_level_id>
			<tag>Dorothy S. Strickland</tag>
			<desc>Strickland's purpose in this article is to share the kinds of things that every individual who cares for young children should know and apply in their child rearing and early education practices.</desc>
			<synopsis>The first section of this article provides a succinct discussion of how the earliest years contribute to children's later success as readers and writers. The second provides some suggestions as to what parents, grandparents, and other caregivers of young children can do to facilitate the language and literacy development of the children they care for. In addition, there are some suggestions for what parents should look for in the child care settings in which they place their children.</synopsis>
			<synopsis_cont></synopsis_cont>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Environmental Print List</name>
			<file_type>PDF</file_type>
			<location>Resources\EarlyChildhoodEducation\Guidelines\docs\Environmental Print List.pdf</location>
			<url>http://www.evenstartnetwork.net/pdf/Environmental%20Print%20List.pdf</url>
			<top_level_id>ECE</top_level_id>
			<second_level_id>G</second_level_id>
			<tag></tag>
			<desc>This list provides ideas of everyday objects that can be used to facilitate a child's literacy development.</desc>
			<synopsis>Letter identification is part of young children&#x2019;s literacy development. It begins with recognizing different shapes and other symbols.  There are many objects that children come across daily that can be used to encourage letter identification and other literacy skills.  Some of these possible objects are listed here.</synopsis>
			<synopsis_cont></synopsis_cont>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Language and Literacy in Young Children: A Framework for Adult-Child Interaction and Support</name>
			<file_type>PDF</file_type>
			<location>Resources\InteractiveLiteracyActivities\Guidelines\docs\Handout  Framework D Strickland.pdf</location>
			<url>http://www.evenstartnetwork.net/pdf/Handout%20%20Framework%20D%20Strickland.pdf</url>
			<top_level_id>ILA</top_level_id>
			<second_level_id>G</second_level_id>
			<tag>Dorothy S. Strickland</tag>
			<desc>A framework for children's literacy development and how adults can support it.</desc>
			<synopsis>This table identifies aspects of school readiness (oral language, alphabetic code, print knowledge, and text comprehension).  Examples of how to facilitate development of these skills for different age groups through adult-child interaction are presented.  The final column lists practical strategies for including these examples and skills into a family literacy program.</synopsis>
			<synopsis_cont></synopsis_cont>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>What the Research Says Families and Family Literacy Educators Should Know About Children's Literacy Development</name>
			<file_type>PDF</file_type>
			<location>Resources\EarlyChildhoodEducation\Research\docs\Strickland PPt.pdf</location>
			<url>http://www.evenstartnetwork.net/pdf/Strickland%20PPt.pdf</url>
			<top_level_id>ECE</top_level_id>
			<second_level_id>R</second_level_id>
			<tag>Dorothy S. Strickland</tag>
			<desc>This presentation by Dorothy Strickland presents research on literacy development in young children.</desc>
			<synopsis>Strickland focuses on the importance of nurturing relationships between children and adults so that children, even those less than a year old, are exposed to the fundamentals of literacy.  Literacy learning for young children is a social, and not just an academic, exercise.  Children who are not given these opportunities early on continue to lag behind their peers in school.  Strickland also provides some tips and examples for encouraging emergent literacy in the context of family literacy programs.</synopsis>
			<synopsis_cont></synopsis_cont>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Working with Families from Diverse Backgrounds</name>
			<file_type>PDF</file_type>
			<location>Resources\EarlyChildhoodEducation\Research\docs\4 PowerPoint_Diverse Families_Oscar Barbarin &amp; Linda Espino.pdf</location>
			<url>http://www.evenstartnetwork.net/pdf/4%20PowerPoint_Diverse%20Families_Oscar%20Barbarin%20&amp;%20Linda%20Espino.pdf</url>
			<top_level_id>ECE</top_level_id>
			<second_level_id>R</second_level_id>
			<tag>Linda M. Espinosa, Oscar A. Barbarin, culture, ESL, minority education, ELL, achievement gap</tag>
			<desc>This presentation discusses the needs of minority and low-income families who attend literacy programs.</desc>
			<synopsis>Espinosa and Barbarin begin the presentation with a discussion of the achievement gap between white students and their peers who are Hispanic or African-American.  They go on to discuss how culture and ethnicity can affect a child's outlook, parenting styles, and other things within a family.  Tips for dealing with cultural differences and tailoring instruction to work with a family's culture are given.  Instructing ELLs is also discussed.</synopsis>
			<synopsis_cont></synopsis_cont>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>An Exercise in Cross-Cultural Communication</name>
			<file_type>PDF</file_type>
			<location>Resources\EarlyChildhoodEducation\Worksheet\docs\Handout 1_Vignette.pdf</location>
			<url>http://www.evenstartnetwork.net/pdf/Handout%201_Vignette.pdf</url>
			<top_level_id>ECE</top_level_id>
			<second_level_id>W</second_level_id>
			<tag>culture</tag>
			<desc>A group activity discussing how to work with parents from different backgrounds.</desc>
			<synopsis>A case study is presented on how a mother interacts with her child during interactive literacy time.  Follow-up questions are presented to prompt thinking about how an instructor should help the mother interact more positively with her child while still being empathatic to the mother's culture and background.</synopsis>
			<synopsis_cont></synopsis_cont>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Parenting Education</name>
			<file_type>PDF</file_type>
			<location>Resources\ParentingEducation\Guidelines\docs\5. Parenting Ed Wasik.pdf</location>
			<url>http://www.evenstartnetwork.net/pdf/5.%20Parenting%20Ed%20Wasik.pdf</url>
			<top_level_id>PE</top_level_id>
			<second_level_id>G</second_level_id>
			<tag>Barbara Hanna Wasik, scaffolding</tag>
			<desc>In this presentation Barbara Wasik provides tips for linking parenting education and interactive literacy activities.</desc>
			<synopsis>Wasik discusses the importance of parenting education and interactive literacy activities.  She describes how to work with the parents beforehand to make sure they understand what they are trying to accomplish with their children in the upcoming activity and how they can apply it to daily interactions with their children.  She also describes what should happen during the interactive reading time.  She uses the See, Show, Say model when reading with children.  She also gives pointers for dealing with adult learners so that parents understand what they are being taught.  The idea of scaffolding support comes up throughout the presentation.</synopsis>
			<synopsis_cont></synopsis_cont>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Using Other Print Material and Stories During Interactive Literacy Activities</name>
			<file_type>PDF</file_type>
			<location>Resources\InteractiveLiteracyActivities\Guidelines\docs\6 Other Print &amp; Stories Knapp-Philo.pdf</location>
			<url>http://www.evenstartnetwork.net/pdf/6%20Other%20Print%20&amp;%20Stories%20Knapp-Philo.pdf</url>
			<top_level_id>ILA</top_level_id>
			<second_level_id>G</second_level_id>
			<tag>Joanne Knapp-Philo</tag>
			<desc>In this presentation Joanne Knapp-Philo discusses ways to use music, stories, and experiences in daily activities to support literacy development.</desc>
			<synopsis>This presentation discusses how to encourage parents to interact with their children to enhance literacy development.  Knapp-Philo describes how to use environmental print (everyday items) to incorporate literacy into daily activities.  Music is another useful tool.  She also suggests getting parents to tell their children stories and share their own experiences as a way to make literacy development relevant to the child's culture and background, and to encourage children to contribute to the stories.</synopsis>
			<synopsis_cont></synopsis_cont>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Tell Us a Story!</name>
			<file_type>PDF</file_type>
			<location>Resources\InteractiveLiteracyActivities\TeachingActivity\docs\Handout 1_Stories.pdf</location>
			<url>http://www.evenstartnetwork.net/pdf/Handout%201_Stories.pdf</url>
			<top_level_id>ILA</top_level_id>
			<second_level_id>TA</second_level_id>
			<tag>Joanne Knapp-Philo</tag>
			<desc>This sheet describes how to use storytelling to encourage literacy.</desc>
			<synopsis>Strategies are given for how to incorporate storytelling into interactive literacy time.  Possible sources of stories are also listed.  Other suggestions to keep children engaged with the story and learning actively are given.</synopsis>
			<synopsis_cont></synopsis_cont>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Sing Us a Song!</name>
			<file_type>PDF</file_type>
			<location>Resources\InteractiveLiteracyActivities\TeachingActivity\docs\Handout 2_Music.pdf</location>
			<url>http://www.evenstartnetwork.net/pdf/Handout%202_Music.pdf</url>
			<top_level_id>ILA</top_level_id>
			<second_level_id>TA</second_level_id>
			<tag>Joanne Knapp-Philo</tag>
			<desc>This sheet offers advice on how to use music to promote emergent literacy.</desc>
			<synopsis>Various strategies to incorporate music into literacy instruction are given.  For each strategy there is also a brief discussion on how exactly this activity helps with literacy development.</synopsis>
			<synopsis_cont></synopsis_cont>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Follow the Car</name>
			<file_type>PDF</file_type>
			<location>Resources\InteractiveLiteracyActivities\TeachingActivity\docs\Handout 3_Follow the car.pdf</location>
			<url>http://www.evenstartnetwork.net/pdf/Handout%203_Follow%20the%20car.pdf</url>
			<top_level_id>ILA</top_level_id>
			<second_level_id>TA</second_level_id>
			<tag>Joanne Knapp-Philo</tag>
			<desc>This table shows how to engage with children during interactive literacy activities.</desc>
			<synopsis>The table shows how to interact with children of different ages to promote emergent literacy.  It gives examples of how to use books, music, and stories during interactive literacy activities.  The basic pattern to follow during each activity is: follow the child's lead; comment and wait; ask questions and wait; respond by adding a little more and wait.</synopsis>
			<synopsis_cont></synopsis_cont>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Supporting Infants' and Toddlers' Literacy Development Through Book Reading</name>
			<file_type>PDF</file_type>
			<location>Resources\InteractiveLiteracyActivities\Guidelines\docs\7 Book Reading 0-3 Knapp-Philo.pdf</location>
			<url>http://www.evenstartnetwork.net/pdf/7%20Book%20Reading%200-3%20Knapp-Philo.pdf</url>
			<top_level_id>ILA</top_level_id>
			<second_level_id>G</second_level_id>
			<tag>Joanne Knapp-Philo</tag>
			<desc>This PowerPoint describes how to interact with a child while reading to encourage literacy.</desc>
			<synopsis>Knapp-Philo presents research showing that children begin to learn literacy skills as infants.  She uses the Follow the CAR strategy to illustrate how to read interactively with a very young child (Comment, Ask, Respond). She encourages waiting for the child to respond and letting the child take the lead in the activity rather than just letting the child be a passive observer.</synopsis>
			<synopsis_cont></synopsis_cont>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Developmental Accomplishments of Literacy Acquisition</name>
			<file_type>PDF</file_type>
			<location>Resources\EarlyChildhoodEducation\Guidelines\docs\Handout 1- Dev accomplish.pdf</location>
			<url>http://www.evenstartnetwork.net/pdf/Handout%201-%20Dev%20accomplish.pdf</url>
			<top_level_id>ECE</top_level_id>
			<second_level_id>G</second_level_id>
			<tag>Joanne Knapp-Philo, assessment</tag>
			<desc>This handout presents a list of literacy accomplishments for 0- to 3-year-olds.</desc>
			<synopsis>This list presents ways that children will interact with books as they develop literacy skills.  The instructor can use this list as a guideline to recognize if a child is meeting the developmental accomplishments.</synopsis>
			<synopsis_cont></synopsis_cont>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Talking and Reading with Infants and Toddlers</name>
			<file_type>PDF</file_type>
			<location>Resources\InteractiveLiteracyActivities\Guidelines\docs\Handout 2_Follow the Car.pdf</location>
			<url>http://www.evenstartnetwork.net/pdf/Handout%202_Follow%20the%20Car.pdf</url>
			<top_level_id>ILA</top_level_id>
			<second_level_id>G</second_level_id>
			<tag>Joanne Knapp-Philo</tag>
			<desc>This handout describes the kinds of things that may be said while performing interactive reading with infants and toddlers.</desc>
			<synopsis>This handout uses the Follow the CAR technique (Comment, Ask, Respond).  Separate examples of what may be said at each step, for both infants and toddlers, are given.  The final page lists some further pointers about how to let the child take the lead in the activity.</synopsis>
			<synopsis_cont></synopsis_cont>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Supporting Children's Literacy Development Through Book Reading: Children 3-7 Years</name>
			<file_type>PDF</file_type>
			<location>Resources\InteractiveLiteracyActivities\Guidelines\docs\Book Reading 3-7 Dr. Landry.pdf</location>
			<url>http://www.evenstartnetwork.net/pdf/Book%20Reading%203-7%20Dr.%20Landry.pdf</url>
			<top_level_id>ILA</top_level_id>
			<second_level_id>G</second_level_id>
			<tag>Susan H. Landry, Susan B. Gunnewig, scaffolding</tag>
			<desc>This presentation discusses ways to promote literacy skills in young children.</desc>
			<synopsis>The presentation begins with descriptions of three different levels of literacy development (language level, book knowledge level, and comprehension level) and specific things that a child will do at each level.  Scaffolding and dialogic reading are then discussed as ways to help children develop literacy skills.</synopsis>
			<synopsis_cont></synopsis_cont>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>PEER Read Aloud Checklist</name>
			<file_type>PDF</file_type>
			<location>Resources\InteractiveLiteracyActivities\Worksheet\docs\Handout 1_Peer.pdf</location>
			<url>http://www.evenstartnetwork.net/pdf/Handout%201_Peer.pdf</url>
			<top_level_id>ILA</top_level_id>
			<second_level_id>W</second_level_id>
			<tag>Susan H. Landry, Susan B. Gunnewig</tag>
			<desc>This worksheet breaks down the PEER sequence of dialogic reading.</desc>
			<synopsis>This worksheet poses a question for each stage of the PEER sequence (Prompt, Evaluate, Expand, Repeat).  The questions help instructors to evaluate whether their dialogic reading interactions fit the PEER sequence.</synopsis>
			<synopsis_cont></synopsis_cont>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>CROWD Read Aloud Checklist</name>
			<file_type>PDF</file_type>
			<location>Resources\InteractiveLiteracyActivities\Worksheet\docs\Handout 2_Crowd.pdf</location>
			<url>http://www.evenstartnetwork.net/pdf/Handout%202_Crowd.pdf</url>
			<top_level_id>ILA</top_level_id>
			<second_level_id>W</second_level_id>
			<tag>Susan H. Landry, Susan B. Gunnewig</tag>
			<desc>This worksheet breaks down the CROWD sequence of dialogic reading.</desc>
			<synopsis>The 5 steps of the CROWD sequence of dialogic reading are: Completion, Recall, Open-ended, Wh- (what, where, why), and Distancing.  In this worksheet each step is followed by a question instructors can ask themselves to evaluate whether their interactions with young children fit this dialogic reading sequence.</synopsis>
			<synopsis_cont></synopsis_cont>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Using the Parenting Education Profile</name>
			<file_type>PDF</file_type>
			<location>Resources\ParentingEducation\Guidelines\docs\PP_Parental_Support_CL_PEP_8-2-06.pdf</location>
			<url>http://www.evenstartnetwork.net/pdf/PP_Parental_Support_CL_PEP_8-2-06.pdf</url>
			<top_level_id>PE</top_level_id>
			<second_level_id>G</second_level_id>
			<tag></tag>
			<desc>The Parenting Education Framework is a system for organizing and assessing
information about parents&#x2019; behaviors, attitudes, and understanding related to
their children&#x2019;s literacy development.
			</desc>
			<synopsis>The purpose of the Parenting Education Profile is to plan strategies for developing parents&#x2019; skills to produce literacy outcomes for children and track the progress of skill development.  This presentation discusses how to achieve this goal through support in the home environment and in formal learning settings, through interactive literacy activities, and through parenting education.  Parents are broken down into five levels based on how supportive they are of their children's literacy, and tips for rating parents and for dealing with each level are given.</synopsis>
			<synopsis_cont></synopsis_cont>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Facilitating Children's Literacy Engagement and Development in Adult-Child Interactions: Reading and Writing Together</name>
			<file_type>PDF</file_type>
			<location>Resources\InteractiveLiteracyActivities\Research\docs\Kaderavek_notes_for_email_8-24.pdf</location>
			<url>http://www.evenstartnetwork.net/pdf/Kaderavek_notes_for_email_8-24.pdf</url>
			<top_level_id>ILA</top_level_id>
			<second_level_id>R</second_level_id>
			<tag>Joan N. Kaderavek, standards</tag>
			<desc>This document discusses the development of writing in young learners.</desc>
			<synopsis>Kaderavek begins by discussing states that have concrete early learning standards in writing. She then presents research on how writing is learned. Then stages of writing development are given with examples of each.  She discusses how to use mediated writing as an interactive teaching activity to encourage writing development, with specific activity examples given.</synopsis>
			<synopsis_cont></synopsis_cont>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Introduction to PLEY</name>
			<file_type>Word</file_type>
			<location>Resources\ParentingEducation\Research\docs\Introduction to PLEY (2).doc</location>
			<url>http://www.evenstartnetwork.net/_version2b/assets/doc/BusinessMeetings/2010/Orientation/Resource%20Materials/VT%20Materials/Parenting%20Education/Introduction%20to%20PLEY%20(2).doc</url>
			<top_level_id>PE</top_level_id>
			<second_level_id>R</second_level_id>
			<tag>Vermont</tag>
			<desc>This document presents an overview of the Parenting for Learning in the Early Years System developed by Vermont.</desc>
			<synopsis>The Parenting for Learning in the Early Years (PLEY) System uses the Parenting Education Profile as its base.  The PLEY system was designed to support significant student gains in literacy-focused skills, connecting the research base to instruction and curriculum and allowing parents to focus directly on the knowledge and skills that work.</synopsis>
			<synopsis_cont></synopsis_cont>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>PLEY Individual Parent Goal Setting</name>
			<file_type>Word</file_type>
			<location>Resources\ParentingEducation\Research\docs\PLEY Individual Parent Goal Setting.doc</location>
			<url>http://www.evenstartnetwork.net/_version2b/assets/doc/BusinessMeetings/2010/Orientation/Resource%20Materials/VT%20Materials/Parenting%20Education/PLEY%20Individual%20Parent%20Goal%20Setting.doc</url>
			<top_level_id>PE</top_level_id>
			<second_level_id>W</second_level_id>
			<tag>Vermont</tag>
			<desc>This worksheet allows parents to identify their goals in working to improve their children's literacy skills.</desc>
			<synopsis>The worksheet gives parents the opportunity to identify their goals for aiding in their children's education in four areas: home enviornment, interactive literacy activities, formal education setting, and parent role. Each area is broken into categories, and a tidbit on what research shows is important in that category is given.</synopsis>
			<synopsis_cont></synopsis_cont>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>PLEY Instructional Strategies and Resources</name>
			<file_type>Word</file_type>
			<location>Resources\ParentingEducation\Research\docs\PLEY Instructional Resources and Strategies.doc</location>
			<url>http://www.evenstartnetwork.net/_version2b/assets/doc/BusinessMeetings/2010/Orientation/Resource%20Materials/VT%20Materials/Parenting%20Education/PLEY%20Instructional%20Resources%20and%20Strategies.doc</url>
			<top_level_id>PE</top_level_id>
			<second_level_id>R</second_level_id>
			<tag>Vermont</tag>
			<desc>This document offers tidbits on what research shows helps children learn.</desc>
			<synopsis>This document offers a parent-centered approach to helping children learn.  It lists what research shows can aid in literacy development, both at home and at school.  It covers different materials that can be used, the parent role, how parents should communicate with the school and other caregivers, and how to use interactive literacy activities to your advantage.</synopsis>
			<synopsis_cont></synopsis_cont>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Parent Self-Assessment in Choices, Rules, and Limits</name>
			<file_type>Word</file_type>
			<location>Resources\ParentingEducation\Worksheet\docs\Self Assessement in Choices_rules and limits.doc</location>
			<url>http://www.evenstartnetwork.net/_version2b/assets/doc/BusinessMeetings/2010/Orientation/Resource%20Materials/VT%20Materials/Parenting%20Education/Self%20Assessement%20in%20Choices_rules%20and%20limits.doc</url>
			<top_level_id>PE</top_level_id>
			<second_level_id>W</second_level_id>
			<tag>Vermont</tag>
			<desc>This is a self-assessment for parents to use to rate how they feel they are doing with setting limits for their children.</desc>
			<synopsis>This worksheet provides a rating scale for how well parents think they are doing with setting limits for their children.  They are then asked to give an example of why they feel frustrated or secure, and what they would like to do to improve. The self-assessment can be used to tailor the parenting education component to each parent's needs.</synopsis>
			<synopsis_cont></synopsis_cont>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Parent Self-Assessment in Child's Success in Learning</name>
			<file_type>Word</file_type>
			<location>Resources\ParentingEducation\Worksheet\docs\Self Assessment in Childs Success in Learning.doc</location>
			<url>http://www.evenstartnetwork.net/_version2b/assets/doc/BusinessMeetings/2010/Orientation/Resource%20Materials/VT%20Materials/Parenting%20Education/Self%20Assessment%20in%20Childs%20Success%20in%20Learning.doc</url>
			<top_level_id>PE</top_level_id>
			<second_level_id>W</second_level_id>
			<tag>Vermont</tag>
			<desc>This is a self-assessment for parents to use to rate how involved they feel they are with their child's education.</desc>
			<synopsis>This worksheet provides a rating scale for how involved parents feel they are with their child's education.  They are then asked to give an example of why they feel frustrated or secure, and what they would like to do to improve. The self-assessment can be used to tailor the parenting education component to each parent's needs.</synopsis>
			<synopsis_cont></synopsis_cont>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Parent Self-Assessment in Parent-School Communication</name>
			<file_type>Word</file_type>
			<location>Resources\ParentingEducation\Worksheet\docs\Self Assessment in Parent School Communications.doc</location>
			<url>http://www.evenstartnetwork.net/_version2b/assets/doc/BusinessMeetings/2010/Orientation/Resource%20Materials/VT%20Materials/Parenting%20Education/Self%20Assessment%20in%20Parent%20School%20Communications.doc</url>
			<top_level_id>PE</top_level_id>
			<second_level_id>W</second_level_id>
			<tag>Vermont</tag>
			<desc>This is a self-assessment for parents to use to rate how successful they feel they are in communicating with their child's school.</desc>
			<synopsis>This worksheet provides parents with a rating scale for how successful they feel they are in communicating with their child's school.  They are then asked to give an example of why they feel frustrated or secure, and what they would like to do to improve. The self-assessment can be used to tailor the parenting education component to each parent's needs.</synopsis>
			<synopsis_cont></synopsis_cont>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Craig Ramey Presentation Part 1</name>
			<file_type>.wmv</file_type>
			<location>Resources\EarlyChildhoodEducation\Research\video\Craig_Section 1.wmv</location>
			<url>http://www.evenstartnetwork.net/_version2b/assets/video/2010/Craig_Section%201.wmv</url>
			<top_level_id>ECE</top_level_id>
			<second_level_id>R</second_level_id>
			<tag>Craig Ramey, achievement gap</tag>
			<desc>This is part 1 of 4 of Craig Ramey's presentation on a longitudinal study he has conducted on the impact of early childhood programs on the lives of underprivileged children.</desc>
			<synopsis>Dr. Ramey begins his presentation by discussing the evolution of early childhood research over the last 40 years.  He discusses some studies he has conducted that deal with early learning, particularly among underprivileged and orphan children.</synopsis>
			<synopsis_cont></synopsis_cont>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Craig Ramey Presentation Part 2</name>
			<file_type>.wmv</file_type>
			<location>Resources\EarlyChildhoodEducation\Research\video\Craig_Section 2.wmv</location>
			<url>http://www.evenstartnetwork.net/_version2b/assets/video/2010/Craig_Section%202.wmv</url>
			<top_level_id>ECE</top_level_id>
			<second_level_id>R</second_level_id>
			<tag>Craig Ramey, achievement gap</tag>
			<desc>This is part 2 of 4 of Craig Ramey's presentation on a longitudinal study he has conducted on the impact of early childhood programs on the lives of underprivileged children.</desc>
			<synopsis>Dr. Ramey starts this section discussing the importance of early childhood educators. He then discusses 7 things that children need from a very young age in order to succeed, based on his research. He also presents statistics on children's vocabulary development based on family income and how this affects them later in life. He discusses how all of a child's experiences educate him or her and affect his or her success.</synopsis>
			<synopsis_cont></synopsis_cont>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Craig Ramey Presentation Part 3</name>
			<file_type>.wmv</file_type>
			<location>Resources\EarlyChildhoodEducation\Research\video\Craig_Section 3.wmv</location>
			<url>http://www.evenstartnetwork.net/_version2b/assets/video/2010/Craig_Section%203.wmv</url>
			<top_level_id>ECE</top_level_id>
			<second_level_id>R</second_level_id>
			<tag>Craig Ramey, achievement gap</tag>
			<desc>This is part 3 of 4 of Craig Ramey's presentation on a longitudinal study he has conducted on the impact of early childhood programs on the lives of underprivileged children.</desc>
			<synopsis>In this section Dr. Ramey discusses the Abecedarian Project, a study that he began in the 1970s. It attempted to control as many variables as possible in order to isolate the effect of early childhood programs on underprivileged children. They did this by providing free health care, free school lunch, transportation, etc. to both the control group and the group that was enrolled in a preschool program. The children were then followed until the age of 30. Some of the data from the study are presented. He then gives some suggestions on how early childhood programs can achieve successful child outcomes.</synopsis>
			<synopsis_cont></synopsis_cont>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Craig Ramey Presentation part 4</name>
			<file_type>.wmv</file_type>
			<location>Resources\EarlyChildhoodEducation\Research\video\Craig_Section 4.wmv</location>
			<url>http://www.evenstartnetwork.net/_version2b/assets/video/2010/Craig_Section%204.wmv</url>
			<top_level_id>ECE</top_level_id>
			<second_level_id>R</second_level_id>
			<tag>Craig Ramey, achievement gap, assessment, culture, ELL, ESL</tag>
			<desc>This is part 4 of 4 of Craig Ramey's presentation on a longitudinal study he has conducted on the impact of early childhood programs on the lives of underprivileged children.</desc>
			<synopsis>In this final section of his presentation, Dr. Ramey answers questions from the audience. He discusses ideas for further research; the usefulness of education programs at various ages; assessment instruments used in the Abecedarian Project and how useful they are for testing different cultural groups; and the issues presented by having families from multiple language backgrounds in one program.</synopsis>
			<synopsis_cont></synopsis_cont>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Early Learning Standards Program Integration</name>
			<file_type>PDF</file_type>
			<location>Resources\InteractiveLiteracyActivities\TeachingActivity\docs\ECSQ-IT program integration _2_.pdf</location>
			<url>http://www.evenstartnetwork.net/_version2b/assets/doc/BusinessMeetings/2010/Day%201/ECSQ-IT%20program%20integration%20_2_.pdf</url>
			<top_level_id>ILA</top_level_id>
			<second_level_id>TA</second_level_id>
			<tag>Michigan, play, standards</tag>
			<desc>This sheet lists examples of activities that can be used around the theme Physical Fitness/Leisure.</desc>
			<synopsis>Examples are given of different kinds of learning activities that can be used with young children that all follow the same theme.  Examples of books that can be used, topics for interactive literacy activities, songs, use of dramatic play, technology usage, and math/science activities are all given. The concepts behind these activities can be used to interconnect the components of a family literacy program around any theme or topic.</synopsis>
			<synopsis_cont></synopsis_cont>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Language Diversity and Literacy Development Presentation Part 1</name>
			<file_type>.wmv</file_type>
			<location>Resources\EarlyChildhoodEducation\Research\video\Nonie_Section 1.wmv</location>
			<url>http://www.evenstartnetwork.net/_version2b/assets/video/2010/Nonie_Section%201.wmv</url>
			<top_level_id>ECE</top_level_id>
			<second_level_id>R</second_level_id>
			<tag>ESL, culture, minority education, Nonie Lesaux</tag>
			<desc>This is the first section of a five part presentation by Nonie Lesaux on teaching young English language learners.</desc>
			<synopsis>Dr. Lesaux begins her presentation by discussing her background and her research on young ELLs. She then discusses the current language demographics in the U.S. She then shows a video of an English-only kindergarten classroom full of Spanish speaking children and strategies that can be used when working with ELLs. This is followed by a discussion of some case studies of students. She also talks about cultural issues and balancing English learning with Spanish heritage.</synopsis>
			<synopsis_cont></synopsis_cont>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Language Diversity and Literacy Development Presentation Part 2</name>
			<file_type>.wmv</file_type>
			<location>Resources\EarlyChildhoodEducation\Research\video\Nonie_Section 2.wmv</location>
			<url>http://www.evenstartnetwork.net/_version2b/assets/video/2010/Nonie_Section%202.wmv</url>
			<top_level_id>ECE</top_level_id>
			<second_level_id>R</second_level_id>
			<tag>ESL, culture, minority education, Nonie Lesaux</tag>
			<desc>This is part 2 of 5 in Nonie Lesaux's presentation on teaching young English language learners.</desc>
			<synopsis>Nonie begins this section of the presentation by discussing current pressing issues in teaching ELLs literacy and oral language skills. This includes a discussion of the achievement gap between children of low-income, immigrant families and their less at-risk peers. She also talks about the skills needed to become a good reader and to become an expressive communicator.</synopsis>
			<synopsis_cont></synopsis_cont>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Language Diversity and Literacy Development Presentation Part 3</name>
			<file_type>.wmv</file_type>
			<location>Resources\EarlyChildhoodEducation\Research\video\Nonie_Section 3.wmv</location>
			<url>http://www.evenstartnetwork.net/_version2b/assets/video/2010/Nonie_Section%203.wmv</url>
			<top_level_id>ECE</top_level_id>
			<second_level_id>R</second_level_id>
			<tag>ESL, culture, minority education, Nonie Lesaux</tag>
			<desc>This is part 3 of 5 in Nonie Lesaux's presentation on teaching young English language learners.</desc>
			<synopsis>This section of the presentation continues to develop the student case studies and what educators can do to help those students. Nonie also discusses her definition of vocabulary and language and how they work to develop comprehension.</synopsis>
			<synopsis_cont></synopsis_cont>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Language Diversity and Literacy Development Presentation Part 4</name>
			<file_type>.wmv</file_type>
			<location>Resources\EarlyChildhoodEducation\Research\video\Nonie_Section 4.wmv</location>
			<url>http://www.evenstartnetwork.net/_version2b/assets/video/2010/Nonie_Section%204.wmv</url>
			<top_level_id>ECE</top_level_id>
			<second_level_id>R</second_level_id>
			<tag>ESL, culture, minority education, Nonie Lesaux</tag>
			<desc>This is part 4 of 5 in Nonie Lesaux's presentation on teaching young English language learners.</desc>
			<synopsis>In this section Dr. Lesaux describes how to make children better word learners based on a 5-level stratum of word knowledge. She uses examples from 2 children's books to show how to improve instruction based on the information she has shared. She then presents a developmental sequence for ELLs. She then goes through some myths about teaching ELLs and dispels them. Afterwards Nonie discusses how children from different language backgrounds learn English. Finally, she presents tips on which language instructors should use when interacting with bilingual students.</synopsis>
			<synopsis_cont></synopsis_cont>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Language Diversity and Literacy Development Presentation Part 5</name>
			<file_type>.wmv</file_type>
			<location>Resources\EarlyChildhoodEducation\Research\video\Nonie_Section 5.wmv</location>
			<url>http://www.evenstartnetwork.net/_version2b/assets/video/2010/Nonie_Section%205.wmv</url>
			<top_level_id>ECE</top_level_id>
			<second_level_id>R</second_level_id>
			<tag>ESL, culture, minority education, Nonie Lesaux, assessment</tag>
			<desc>This is part 5 of 5 in Nonie Lesaux's presentation on teaching young English language learners.</desc>
			<synopsis>This last part of Dr. Lesaux's presentation continues to go over characteristics of ELLs and their learning experiences. She then discusses how to modify instruction to help ELLs succeed. She focuses on creating a long-term instructional plan for students. Nonie also talks about the efficacy of types of  assessment instruments for young ELL literacy. She also discusses the importance of speaking practice for ELLs of all ages. There is also a piece on how to deal with the parents of ELL students and the importance of supporting dual-language households. Finally, she gives tips for picking books to use with young ELLs.</synopsis>
			<synopsis_cont></synopsis_cont>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Language Diversity and Literacy Development: Research-Based Practices for Young English-Language Learners</name>
			<file_type>PDF</file_type>
			<location>Resources\EarlyChildhoodEducation\Research\docs\2_Evenstart_lesaux.pdf</location>
			<url>http://www.evenstartnetwork.net/_version2b/assets/doc/BusinessMeetings/2010/Day%202/Language%20Diversity%20and%20Literacy%20Development/2_Evenstart_lesaux.pdf</url>
			<top_level_id>ECE</top_level_id>
			<second_level_id>R</second_level_id>
			<tag>ESL, culture, minority education, Nonie Lesaux</tag>
			<desc>This presentation offers strategies for effectively teaching young English language learners.</desc>
			<synopsis>The presentation begins with a detailed description of the English language learner (ELL) population in the U.S.  Lesaux then talks about the different levels of word knowledge and how to build vocabulary with ELLs.  She also gives tips for deciding what language to use with the child and some ideas for successful practices. She also gives suggestions for deciding what kind of books to use with ELLs. This PDF goes along with Lesaux's video presentation.</synopsis>
			<synopsis_cont></synopsis_cont>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Book List for Young English-Language Learners</name>
			<file_type>Word</file_type>
			<location>Resources\EarlyChildhoodEducation\Guidelines\docs\Book_list.doc</location>
			<url>http://www.evenstartnetwork.net/_version2b/assets/doc/BusinessMeetings/2010/Day%202/Language%20Diversity%20and%20Literacy%20Development/Book_list.doc</url>
			<top_level_id>ECE</top_level_id>
			<second_level_id>G</second_level_id>
			<tag>ESL, Nonie Lesaux</tag>
			<desc>A booklist to use with young English language learners (ELLs).</desc>
			<synopsis>The list of suggested books to use with young ELLs includes both wordless books and bilingual (English/Spanish) books.</synopsis>
			<synopsis_cont></synopsis_cont>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Research-Based Practices for Working with ELL Adult Education Part 1</name>
			<file_type>.wmv</file_type>
			<location>Resources\AdultEducation\Research\video\Robin_Section 1.wmv</location>
			<url>http://www.evenstartnetwork.net/_version2b/assets/video/2010/Robin_Section%201.wmv</url>
			<top_level_id>AE</top_level_id>
			<second_level_id>R</second_level_id>
			<tag>ESL, Robin Lovrien Schwarz, culture</tag>
			<desc>This is the first of four parts in Dr. Schwarz's presentation on teaching adult English language learners (ELLs).</desc>
			<synopsis>Schwarz begins the presentation by discussing her background.  She then goes through an overview on factors that make adult ELLs particulary challenging to work with, including lack of literacy in the first language, cultural differences, past experiences, views on learning, etc.  Then she talks about the importance of tailoring instruction to each student's needs. The next section hits on aspects of ESL programs and classrooms that have been shown to be successful in research.</synopsis>
			<synopsis_cont></synopsis_cont>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Research-Based Practices for Working with ELL Adult Education Part 2</name>
			<file_type>.wmv</file_type>
			<location>Resources\AdultEducation\Research\video\Robin_Section 2.wmv</location>
			<url>http://www.evenstartnetwork.net/_version2b/assets/video/2010/Robin_Section%202.wmv</url>
			<top_level_id>AE</top_level_id>
			<second_level_id>R</second_level_id>
			<tag>ESL, Robin Lovrien Schwarz, culture</tag>
			<desc>This is the second of four parts in Dr. Schwarz's presentation on teaching adult English language learners (ELLs).</desc>
			<synopsis>During this section of her presentation, Schwarz discusses activities that can be used to keep adult learners engaged in their education. She then moves into a talk on how to support reading and phonological development in adults using specific games and activities. Next she talks about how the way a student's first language works impacts English acquisition, especially since English is such a difficult language to learn. The subsequent part covers the subskills that must be taught in order for people to learn to read. She closes with specific ways you can adapt reading instruction based on the student's level of literacy in the first language.</synopsis>
			<synopsis_cont></synopsis_cont>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Research-Based Practices for Working with ELL Adult Education Part 3</name>
			<file_type>.wmv</file_type>
			<location>Resources\AdultEducation\Research\video\Robin_Section 3.wmv</location>
			<url>http://www.evenstartnetwork.net/_version2b/assets/video/2010/Robin_Section%203.wmv</url>
			<top_level_id>AE</top_level_id>
			<second_level_id>R</second_level_id>
			<tag>ESL, Robin Lovrien Schwarz, culture</tag>
			<desc>This is the third of four parts in Dr. Schwarz's presentation on teaching adult English language learners (ELLs).</desc>
			<synopsis>In this section of the presentation Dr. Schwarz discusses how adults learn language and how their learning differs from that of young children. The process of adult language acquisition is discussed. She then moves on to offering tips on what instructors can do to ensure adult learners' success in acquiring language.  She provides examples of activities to build vocabulary, develop understanding, and keep learners engaged. This is followed by a section on the relationship between culture and metacognitive skills, and how this impacts the classroom.</synopsis>
			<synopsis_cont></synopsis_cont>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Research-Based Practices for Working with ELL Adult Education Part 4</name>
			<file_type>.wmv</file_type>
			<location>Resources\AdultEducation\Research\video\Robin_Section 4.wmv</location>
			<url>http://www.evenstartnetwork.net/_version2b/assets/video/2010/Robin_Section%204.wmv</url>
			<top_level_id>AE</top_level_id>
			<second_level_id>R</second_level_id>
			<tag>ESL, Robin Lovrien Schwarz, culture</tag>
			<desc>This is the final section of Dr. Schwarz's presentation on teaching adult English language learners (ELLs).</desc>
			<synopsis>In this, the final part of her presentation, Schwarz discusses how to work with adult ESL students who have no prior literacy in any language. She begins by talking about how a non-literate adult's brain functions differently from a literate adult's and how instructors must work with them on the most basic classroom-related skills. She talks about how this "education as a culture" affects ways that these students can be tested. She goes back to discussing the difficulties in learning English, such as differences in upper- and lowercase letters. She then presents suggestions for activities that are effective with this population and gives general tips for working with these students.</synopsis>
			<synopsis_cont></synopsis_cont>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>10 Ways to Practice Phonological Skills</name>
			<file_type>PDF</file_type>
			<location>Resources\AdultEducation\TeachingActivity\docs\10 Ways to Practice Phonological Skills.pdf</location>
			<url>http://www.evenstartnetwork.net/_version2b/assets/doc/BusinessMeetings/2010/Day%202/Reaseach-Based%20Practices%20for%20Working%20with%20ELL%20Adult%20education/10%20Ways%20to%20Practice%20Phonological%20Skills.pdf</url>
			<top_level_id>AE</top_level_id>
			<second_level_id>TA</second_level_id>
			<tag>ESL, Robin Lovrien Schwarz, special education</tag>
			<desc>Robin Lavrien Schwarz put together this list of 10 practices to use when teaching adult English language learners.</desc>
			<synopsis>The 10 practices for adult ELLs listed here include activities that instructors can do with their students as well strategies the instructor can use in his or her teaching, such as deleting a syllable or sound from a word.</synopsis>
			<synopsis_cont></synopsis_cont>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Attending to Adult Learners: Affective Domain in the ESL Classroom</name>
			<file_type>PDF</file_type>
			<location>Resources\AdultEducation\Research\docs\Affective domain in adult esl.pdf</location>
			<url>http://www.evenstartnetwork.net/_version2b/assets/doc/BusinessMeetings/2010/Day%202/Reaseach-Based%20Practices%20for%20Working%20with%20ELL%20Adult%20education/Affective%20domain%20in%20adult%20esl.pdf</url>
			<top_level_id>AE</top_level_id>
			<second_level_id>R</second_level_id>
			<tag>Eva Bernat, ESL, ELL</tag>
			<desc>Bernat discusses things that may affect the way adult learners comprehend new information and how adult ESL teachers should take these factors into account.</desc>
			<synopsis>Adult ESL students have well-established ideas and preferences about their learning, a plethora of experience to draw on, and some fears and anxieties which can impact on their engagement in, commitment to, and achievement of a second language. ESL teachers need to develop a sensitive awareness of these factors and incorporate knowledge thereof into their teaching practice. Bernat discusses how these factors can be taken into account while teaching.</synopsis>
			<synopsis_cont></synopsis_cont>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Definitions of Culture</name>
			<file_type>PDF</file_type>
			<location>Resources\AdultEducation\Research\docs\Definitions of culture.pdf</location>
			<url>http://www.evenstartnetwork.net/_version2b/assets/doc/BusinessMeetings/2010/Day%202/Reaseach-Based%20Practices%20for%20Working%20with%20ELL%20Adult%20education/Definitions%20of%20culture.pdf</url>
			<top_level_id>AE</top_level_id>
			<second_level_id>R</second_level_id>
			<tag>ESL, Robin Lovrien Schwarz, culture, ELL</tag>
			<desc>Schwarz lists many scholarly definitions of culture and how they apply to ESL classrooms.</desc>
			<synopsis>The many definitons of culture are followed by a discussion of what cultural studies is comprised of.  This is then followed by a section on how to apply this view of culture to adult ESL teaching. Some tips for how teachers should be trained to think about and deal with culture are also given.</synopsis>
			<synopsis_cont></synopsis_cont>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Research-Based Practices for Working with Adult ELLs</name>
			<file_type>PDF</file_type>
			<location>Resources\AdultEducation\Research\docs\Evenstart.pdf</location>
			<url>http://www.evenstartnetwork.net/_version2b/assets/doc/BusinessMeetings/2010/Day%202/Reaseach-Based%20Practices%20for%20Working%20with%20ELL%20Adult%20education/Evenstart.pdf</url>
			<top_level_id>AE</top_level_id>
			<second_level_id>R</second_level_id>
			<tag>ESL, Robin Lovrien Schwarz, culture, ELL</tag>
			<desc>This presentation by Robin Lavrien Schwarz provides best practices for teaching adult English language learners and presents research on the topic.</desc>
			<synopsis>This presentation discusses how to best instruct adult English language learners.  Schwarz emphasizes that learning to read English as a second language is not the same process as learning to read it as a native speaker.  She focuses on how to tailor instruction to meet each adult's needs, based on the adult's culture, prior experience, and literacy level. There is also a section on to teach those adults who have no prior literacy in any language.  Specific tactics for teaching reading and phonological skills are also included. This PDF goes along with Schwarz's video presentation.</synopsis>
			<synopsis_cont></synopsis_cont>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Cross-Cultural Awareness and the English-as-a-Second-Language Classroom</name>
			<file_type>PDF</file_type>
			<location>Resources\AdultEducation\Research\docs\Irving cross cultural.pdf</location>
			<url>http://www.evenstartnetwork.net/_version2b/assets/doc/BusinessMeetings/2010/Day%202/Reaseach-Based%20Practices%20for%20Working%20with%20ELL%20Adult%20education/Irving%20cross%20cultural%20.pdf</url>
			<top_level_id>AE</top_level_id>
			<second_level_id>R</second_level_id>
			<tag>ESL, Kathy J. Irving, culture, ELL</tag>
			<desc>This article cites a need for a model to help ESL students and teachers to become more aware of their and others' cultural influences and discusses how this may be achieved.</desc>
			<synopsis>This paper looks at culture shock as a positive phenomenon that can lead to cultural awareness.  Irving looks at how cultural awareness can help ESL teachers make sure that their students understand the deeper, cultural meaning behind words rather than just their pronounciation and dictionary meaning.  She also offers tips on integrating cultural awareness into the ESL classroom.</synopsis>
			<synopsis_cont></synopsis_cont>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Why School is Hard for Non/Preliterate Adult ESOL Learners</name>
			<file_type>PDF</file_type>
			<location>Resources\AdultEducation\Research\docs\#3 LL learners.pdf</location>
			<url>P:\225 evenstart\working\2010 Annual Busieness Meeting Materials\Day 2\Reaseach-Based Practices for Working with ELL Adult education\# 3 LL learners.pdf</url>
			<top_level_id>AE</top_level_id>
			<second_level_id>R</second_level_id>
			<tag>ESL, Robin Lovrien Schwarz, culture, ELL</tag>
			<desc>This presentation put together by Robin Lavrien Schwarz discusses the challenges non- or pre-literate adults face in the classroom.</desc>
			<synopsis>Schwarz discusses areas that preliterate adults have trouble with in school, along with ways that teachers can work with them on developing skills in those areas.  Areas discussed are: visual discrimination, fine motor and visual motor integration, and phonological awareness. Cultural differences and how they impact language acquisition are also discussed and further resources are listed.</synopsis>
			<synopsis_cont></synopsis_cont>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Phonological Skills, Phonemes, and Phonology</name>
			<file_type>PDF</file_type>
			<location>Resources\AdultEducation\Research\docs\Phonological Skills fact sheet .pdf</location>
			<url>P:\225 evenstart\working\2010 Annual Busieness Meeting Materials\Day 2\Reaseach-Based Practices for Working with ELL Adult education\Phonological Skills fact sheet.pdf</url>
			<top_level_id>AE</top_level_id>
			<second_level_id>R</second_level_id>
			<tag>ESL, Robin Lovrien Schwarz, ELL</tag>
			<desc>This document gives definitions of terms related to phonological awareness.</desc>
			<synopsis>The definitions listed here are all related to the development of phonological awareness. There is also a timeline of specific skills that children develop as they become more phonologically aware.</synopsis>
			<synopsis_cont></synopsis_cont>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>The Iceberg Conception of the Nature of Culture</name>
			<file_type>PDF</file_type>
			<location>\Resources\AdultEducation\Research\docs\The Iceberg Conception of the Nature of Culture.pdf</location>
			<url>P:\225 evenstart\working\2010 Annual Busieness Meeting Materials\Day 2\Reaseach-Based Practices for Working with ELL Adult education\The Iceberg Conception of the Nature of Culture.pdf</url>
			<top_level_id>AE</top_level_id>
			<second_level_id>R</second_level_id>
			<tag>ESL, Robin Lovrien Schwarz, ELL, culture</tag>
			<desc>This handout lists ways that culture can affect a learner's outlook on the world.</desc>
			<synopsis>This handout presents many specific concepts and worldviews that are affected by a learner's culture.  They are divided into ones that are primarily in awareness and those that aren't. The purpose of this is to inform teachers of what they need to think about when developing instruction for students from diverse cultures.</synopsis>
			<synopsis_cont></synopsis_cont>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Using Games as Multisensory Teaching Aids</name>
			<file_type>PDF</file_type>
			<location>Resources\AdultEducation\TeachingActivity\docs\Using games PDF format.pdf</location>
			<url>P:\225 evenstart\working\2010 Annual Busieness Meeting Materials\Day 2\Reaseach-Based Practices for Working with ELL Adult education\Using games PDF format.pdf</url>
			<top_level_id>AE</top_level_id>
			<second_level_id>TA</second_level_id>
			<tag>ESL, Robin Lovrien Schwarz, play, ELL</tag>
			<desc>This document explains how to use games to further learning outcomes.</desc>
			<synopsis>This document describes how to use games effectively in the classroom.  Overarching concepts on the usefulness of games are identified first, then certain games are specifically applied to ESL learning, such as go fish and bingo.</synopsis>
			<synopsis_cont></synopsis_cont>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Early Childhood Assessment: Why, What, and How</name>
			<file_type>PDF</file_type>
			<location>Resources\EarlyChildhoodEducation\Guidelines\docs\Developmental Outcomes for Even Start.pdf</location>
			<url>http://www.evenstartnetwork.net/assets/2009BUS_MTG/Binder/Day%201/Developmental%20Outcomes%20for%20Even%20Start.pdf</url>
			<top_level_id>ECE</top_level_id>
			<second_level_id>G</second_level_id>
			<tag>assessment, Susan van Hernel</tag>
			<desc>This PowerPoint describes a National Academies study on assessment entitled Early Childhood Assessment: Why, What, and How.</desc>
			<synopsis>This presentation gives tips on how to assess early childhood education programs to end up with better outcomes for children.  Topics covered are instrument selection and use of child specific information, among others.  The report is linked at the end of the presentation.</synopsis>
			<synopsis_cont></synopsis_cont>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Leading in Changing Times</name>
			<file_type>PPT</file_type>
			<location>Resources\EarlyChildhoodEducation\Guidelines\docs\LeadinginChangingTimes.ppt</location>
			<url>http://www.evenstartnetwork.net/2008meeting/LeadinginChangingTimes.ppt</url>
			<top_level_id>ECE</top_level_id>
			<second_level_id>G</second_level_id>
			<tag>Janice Jackson</tag>
			<desc>Janice Jackson's presentation gives tips for being a leader in the field of early childhood education.</desc>
			<synopsis>This presentation highlights skills that kids need to learn in order to succeed in the 21st century and how leaders in schools can help them achieve those goals.  Jackson also gives tips for managing groups of peers. This PowerPoint goes along with Jackson's video presentation.</synopsis>
			<synopsis_cont></synopsis_cont>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Family Literacy: A Research Agenda to Build the Future</name>
			<file_type>PDF</file_type>
			<location>Resources\EarlyChildhoodEducation\Research\docs\Goodling Institute FL Research Agenda.pdf</location>
			<url>http://www.evenstartnetwork.net/2007AnnualMeeting/Resources/Goodling%20Institute%20FL%20Research%20Agenda.pdf</url>
			<top_level_id>AE, ECE</top_level_id>
			<second_level_id>R</second_level_id>
			<tag></tag>
			<desc>This report is organized into discussions of the state of family literacy, problems in researching family literacy, and next steps in formulating the research issues to be
addressed in future studies.
			</desc>
			<synopsis>This report gathers the outcomes of a two day meeting of experts in the family literacy field.  The report comes to several conclusions: family literacy programs need to be more strongly research-based; indicators are needed to be able to assess how well the four components of family literacy programs are integrated and how well the program is integrated with local social services; proper curricula and assessment instruments are lacking; and more research is needed to decipher what populations are best served by what types of family literacy programs.</synopsis>
			<synopsis_cont></synopsis_cont>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Head Start FACES Study Report</name>
			<file_type>PDF</file_type>
			<location>Resources\EarlyChildhoodEducation\Research\docs\Head Start FACES study report.pdf</location>
			<url>http://www.evenstartnetwork.net/2007AnnualMeeting/Resources/Head%20Start%20FACES%20study%20report.pdf</url>
			<top_level_id>ECE</top_level_id>
			<second_level_id>R</second_level_id>
			<tag>special education, assessment</tag>
			<desc>This brochure presents findings from a 2003 review of Head Start families.</desc>
			<synopsis>The findings in this report discuss how well Head Start children perform on literacy assessments before and after participating in the program. It also assesses parent involvement and profiles the typical Head Start family.  There is also a summary of Head Start teacher qualifications and program characteristics. The report closes with a page on teaching children with special needs.</synopsis>
			<synopsis_cont></synopsis_cont>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>State of Preschools 2006</name>
			<file_type>PDF</file_type>
			<location>Resources\EarlyChildhoodEducation\Research\docs\Preschools 2006.pdf</location>
			<url>http://www.evenstartnetwork.net/2007AnnualMeeting/Resources/Preschools%202006.pdf</url>
			<top_level_id>ECE</top_level_id>
			<second_level_id>R</second_level_id>
			<tag></tag>
			<desc>This in-depth report profiles preschool programs in each state.</desc>
			<synopsis>This national profile provides a summary of state-funded prekindergarten data across the United States in the 2005-2006 academic year. The focus is on access to state preschool, quality standards, and spending, but national (rather than statewide) totals and averages are presented. Quality standards varied enormously across the states. Almost half of the state preschool education initiatives failed to meet the important benchmark of requiring a bachelor&#x2019;s degree or higher for all lead teachers. Still, total spending per child enrolled was much less for state prekindergarten than for grades K-12 in public schools.</synopsis>
			<synopsis_cont></synopsis_cont>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Concepts of Print, Books, and Literacy</name>
			<file_type>Word</file_type>
			<location>Resources\EarlyChildhoodEducation\Research\docs\ConceptsofPrint.doc</location>
			<url>http://www.evenstartnetwork.net/_version2b/assets/tribal/ConceptsofPrint.doc</url>
			<top_level_id>ECE</top_level_id>
			<second_level_id>R</second_level_id>
			<tag>Mark Condon, Bill Mahojah</tag>
			<desc>This document presents ideas about print that literate children should hold.</desc>
			<synopsis>This document lists concepts about print, books, and literacy that are helpful to children in seeing the point of having strong literacy skills.  These concepts help teachers instruct their students about the ideas behind literacy and its usefulness in society, rather than just the words and vocabulary of literacy.</synopsis>
			<synopsis_cont></synopsis_cont>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Creating a WEBBE</name>
			<file_type>Word</file_type>
			<location>Resources\InteractiveLiteracyActivities\TeachingActivity\docs\CreatingaWebbe.doc</location>
			<url>http://www.evenstartnetwork.net/_version2b/assets/tribal/CreatingaWebbe.doc</url>
			<top_level_id>ILA</top_level_id>
			<second_level_id>TA</second_level_id>
			<tag>Mark Condon, Bill Mahojah</tag>
			<desc>This document teaches you how to make your own book on the computer to use in the classroom.</desc>
			<synopsis>This document describes how to make a Webbe (Web Book for Everyone).  A Webbe is a picture book that you can print of the computer to use with young children to teach them about personalized experiences. Children can also make their own to share.</synopsis>
			<synopsis_cont></synopsis_cont>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Sample WEBBE</name>
			<file_type>Word</file_type>
			<location>Resources\InteractiveLiteracyActivities\TeachingActivity\docs\SampleWebbe.doc</location>
			<url>http://www.evenstartnetwork.net/_version2b/assets/tribal/SampleWebbe.doc</url>
			<top_level_id>ILA</top_level_id>
			<second_level_id>TA</second_level_id>
			<tag>Mark Condon, Bill Mahojah</tag>
			<desc>A Webbe template.</desc>
			<synopsis>This provides a template for an instructor and/or students to make their own picture books to print out.</synopsis>
			<synopsis_cont></synopsis_cont>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Elements of High-Quality Emergent Literacy Instruction in Early Education Settings</name>
			<file_type>PDF</file_type>
			<location>Resources\EarlyChildhoodEducation\Research\docs\denverevenstart.ppt [Compatibility M.PDF</location>
			<url>http://www.evenstartnetwork.net/_version2b/assets/tribal/denverevenstart.ppt%20%5BCompatibility%20M.PDF</url>
			<top_level_id>ECE</top_level_id>
			<second_level_id>R</second_level_id>
			<tag>special education, culture, Laura Justice</tag>
			<desc>This presentation by Laura Justice details how to instruct the first stage of literacy, emergent literacy.</desc>
			<synopsis>This presentation covers both emergent reading and writing.  Justice uses research to promote useful teaching strategies for each area of emergent literacy.  Each area is also given a list of tasks that a successful child should be able to perform. She also gives tips for culturally relevant book selection and creating a literacy-rich environment that promotes learning.</synopsis>
			<synopsis_cont></synopsis_cont>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Elements of High-Quality Emergent Literacy Instruction in Early Education Settings: A Weekly Planning Guide</name>
			<file_type>Word</file_type>
			<location>Resources\EarlyChildhoodEducation\Worksheet\docs\planningguide.docx</location>
			<url>http://www.evenstartnetwork.net/_version2b/assets/tribal/planningguide.docx</url>
			<top_level_id>ECE</top_level_id>
			<second_level_id>W</second_level_id>
			<tag>Laura Justice</tag>
			<desc>A weekly planning guide for instructors to use to ensure that they are teaching to each of the areas of emergent literacy.</desc>
			<synopsis>This planner has space for marking how each area of emergent literacy (oral language, emergent writing, print knowledge, alphabet knowledge, phonological awareness) will be taught in each of four different activities (print-rich environment, literacy-enriched play, interactive reading, and mediated writing).</synopsis>
			<synopsis_cont></synopsis_cont>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Promising Interventions for Promoting Emergent Literacy Skills: Three Evidence-Based Approaches</name>
			<file_type>PDF</file_type>
			<location>Resources\EarlyChildhoodEducation\Research\docs\justice&amp;pullen.pdf</location>
			<url>http://www.evenstartnetwork.net/_version2b/assets/tribal/justice&amp;pullen.pdf</url>
			<top_level_id>ECE</top_level_id>
			<second_level_id>R</second_level_id>
			<tag>Laura Justice, Paige C. Pullen</tag>
			<desc>This article defines emergent literacy, discusses the meaning of evidence-based practice, and describes three promising evidence-based approaches for emergent literacy intervention.</desc>
			<synopsis>This article describes three approaches to teaching emergent literacy that have a significant
amount of supportive empirical evidence. The three approaches are: adult&#x2013;child shared storybook reading, literacy enriched play settings, and teacher-directed structured phonological awareness  curricula.  After emergent literacy and evidence-based practice are defined, the three approaches
are presented. The article then describes the level of empirical support for the effectiveness of interventions of that type for promoting emergent literacy skills in young children.
			</synopsis>
			<synopsis_cont></synopsis_cont>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Using Shared Storybook Reading to Promote Emergent Literacy</name>
			<file_type>PDF</file_type>
			<location>Resources\InteractiveLiteracyActivities\Research\docs\justiceusingsharedlibiss.pdf</location>
			<url>http://www.evenstartnetwork.net/_version2b/assets/tribal/justiceusingsharedlibiss.pdf</url>
			<top_level_id>ILA</top_level_id>
			<second_level_id>R</second_level_id>
			<tag>Laura Justice, special education, Joan Kaderavek</tag>
			<desc>This article describes several techniques for structuring shared storybook reading interactions to best promote emergent literacy development for young children with disabilities.</desc>
			<synopsis>In this article the authors present techniques for increasing the appeal and interactive nature of shared storybook reading and ways to promote
children's awareness of the literacy conventions naturally occurring within the shared storybook reading context. These techniques should help children with disabilities improve their emergent literacy.
			</synopsis>
			<synopsis_cont></synopsis_cont>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Making Reading and Writing Real</name>
			<file_type>PPT</file_type>
			<location>Resources\EarlyChildhoodEducation\Research\docs\MahojahandCondonPPT.ppt</location>
			<url>http://www.evenstartnetwork.net/_version2b/assets/tribal/MahojahandCondonPPT.ppt</url>
			<top_level_id>ECE</top_level_id>
			<second_level_id>R</second_level_id>
			<tag>Mark Condon, Bill Mahojah, achievement gap, Native American education</tag>
			<desc>This presentation discusses the achievement gap and how preschools and families can help to close it.</desc>
			<synopsis>This presentation focuses particularly on Native American education. It begins by detailing the achievement gap and the factors that influence a child's success in school at a very young age.  The presentation also discusses the importance of books in the home and the support of parents. It focuses on how dads in particular can help their children learn.  The presentation closes with a demonstration of how to have children make picture books that can be printed out on the computer (a Webbe).</synopsis>
			<synopsis_cont></synopsis_cont>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Action Steps and Strategies</name>
			<file_type>Word</file_type>
			<location>Resources\AdultEducation\Guidelines\docs\DDAction steps.doc</location>
			<url>http://www.evenstartnetwork.net/doc/2008_ATM/DianeDAngelopresentationandhandouts/DDAction%20steps.doc</url>
			<top_level_id>AE</top_level_id>
			<second_level_id>G</second_level_id>
			<tag>Diane D'Angelo</tag>
			<desc>This handout lists strategies both for adult and parenting education, and early learning classrooms.</desc>
			<synopsis>This sheet presents big-picture ideas for how to make adult, parenting, and early education instruction successful.  Strategies for the home, classrooms, and for staff development are given.</synopsis>
			<synopsis_cont></synopsis_cont>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Dialogic Reading Planning Sheet</name>
			<file_type>Word</file_type>
			<location>Resources\InteractiveLiteracyActivities\TeachingActivity\docs\GreyDialogic Reading Planning Sheet.doc</location>
			<url>http://www.evenstartnetwork.net/doc/2008_ATM/ShelleyGraypresentationandmaterials/GreyDialogic%20Reading%20Planning%20Sheet.doc</url>
			<top_level_id>ILA</top_level_id>
			<second_level_id>TA</second_level_id>
			<tag>Shelley Gray</tag>
			<desc>A sheet for instructors to use when planning a dialogic reading activity.</desc>
			<synopsis>This sheet prompts instructors to consider all the ways a book will be used during dialogic reading time, what prompts will be used to engage the students, and what the teaching objectives for the lesson are.</synopsis>
			<synopsis_cont></synopsis_cont>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Dialogic Reading</name>
			<file_type>PPT</file_type>
			<location>Resources\InteractiveLiteracyActivities\Guidelines\docs\GreyEarly Start 4 09 08.ppt</location>
			<url>http://www.evenstartnetwork.net/doc/2008_ATM/ShelleyGraypresentationandmaterials/GreyEarly%20Start%204%2009%2008.ppt</url>
			<top_level_id>ILA</top_level_id>
			<second_level_id>G</second_level_id>
			<tag>Shelley Gray</tag>
			<desc>This presentation by Shelley Gray offers advice on integrating dialogic reading into early childhood instruction.</desc>
			<synopsis>The presentation begins by offering advice on book selection for classrooms and families.  It then discusses dialogic reading techniques.  Finally, Gray describes how instructors can prepare a dialogic reading plan to use in their classrooms.</synopsis>
			<synopsis_cont></synopsis_cont>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Preschool Language and Literacy Diagram</name>
			<file_type>PDF</file_type>
			<location>Resources\InteractiveLiteracyActivities\Guidelines\docs\2_ece_diagram-2.pdf</location>
			<url>http://www.evenstartnetwork.net/doc/2008_ATM/DoingWhatWorks/2_ece_diagram-2.pdf</url>
			<top_level_id>ILA</top_level_id>
			<second_level_id>G</second_level_id>
			<tag></tag>
			<desc>An illustrated diagram on the essential parts of preschool language and literacy.</desc>
			<synopsis>This illustration models what should be going on in an early childhood classroom.  Various areas of phonological awareness are shown, along with aspects of interactive reading activities.</synopsis>
			<synopsis_cont></synopsis_cont>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Interactive Reading: A PEER Sequence Planner</name>
			<file_type>PDF</file_type>
			<location>Resources\InteractiveLiteracyActivities\Guidelines\docs\522_idr_mats_peer-1.pdf</location>
			<url>http://www.evenstartnetwork.net/doc/2008_ATM/DoingWhatWorks/522_idr_mats_peer-1.pdf</url>
			<top_level_id>ILA</top_level_id>
			<second_level_id>G</second_level_id>
			<tag>scaffolding</tag>
			<desc>This planner is designed to help a teacher prepare for a reading lesson using the PEER sequence and prompts.</desc>
			<synopsis>This booklet details how to use the PEER and CROWD sequences in interactive reading. The acronyms can help teachers remember the sequence and types of prompts to use.  As the child becomes increasingly familiar with a book, the adult reads less, listens more, and gradually uses higher level prompts to encourage the child to go beyond naming objects in the pictures to thinking more about what is happening in the pictures and how this relates to the child&#x2019;s own experiences.</synopsis>
			<synopsis_cont></synopsis_cont>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Preparing a Dialogic Reading Lesson</name>
			<file_type>PDF</file_type>
			<location>Resources\InteractiveLiteracyActivities\Guidelines\docs\523_idr_mats_prepare.pdf</location>
			<url>http://www.evenstartnetwork.net/doc/2008_ATM/DoingWhatWorks/523_idr_mats_prepare.pdf</url>
			<top_level_id>ILA</top_level_id>
			<second_level_id>G</second_level_id>
			<tag>scaffolding</tag>
			<desc>This booklet shows how to instruct a child through 3 levels of dialogic reading.</desc>
			<synopsis>Advance preparation for dialogic reading helps an early childhood teacher concentrate on interacting with children in a responsive way to develop
oral language skills and increase vocabulary. This handout uses a 3-level framework.  It shows examples of what teacher-child dialogues might look like using the storybook Sheep in a Jeep; each sample dialog or conversation is relevant to one page of the storybook.  Within this framework the conversation begins at Level 1 and slowly
progresses to Level 3 over repeated readings.  Over repeated readings of the story, the questions and responses increase in complexity, scaffolding children to become storytellers.
			</synopsis>
			<synopsis_cont></synopsis_cont>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Building Community Support: The Role of Culture</name>
			<file_type>PPT</file_type>
			<location>Resources\AdultEducation\Guidelines\docs\Jerry_Hill_Tribal_Even_Start_Annual_Meeting.ppt</location>
			<url>http://www.evenstartnetwork.net/tribal_files/JerryHill_Presentation_Materials/Jerry_Hill_Tribal_Even_Start_Annual_Meeting.ppt</url>
			<top_level_id>AE</top_level_id>
			<second_level_id>G</second_level_id>
			<tag>Jerry Hill, culture, minority education, Native American education</tag>
			<desc>Jerry Hill presents on how to use a cultural understand of a community to ensure its support of a family literacy program.</desc>
			<synopsis>Hill specifically focuses on Native American education and how understanding tribal culture can help encourage the community to support a family literacy program. Tips are also given for effective decision making within the program.</synopsis>
			<synopsis_cont></synopsis_cont>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Incorporating Scientifically-Based Reading Research into Adult Education</name>
			<file_type>Word</file_type>
			<location>Resources\AdultEducation\Guidelines\docs\Incorporating SBRR into Adult Education.doc</location>
			<url>http://www.windwalker.com/evenstart/LPD/doc/document-center/Incorporating%20SBRR%20into%20Adult%20Education.doc</url>
			<top_level_id>AE</top_level_id>
			<second_level_id>G</second_level_id>
			<tag></tag>
			<desc>Key ideas about how to incorporate scientifically-based reading research (SBRR) into adult education classrooms are presented.</desc>
			<synopsis>This document presents key points about SBRR in adult education classrooms.  They fall under the categories of: alphabetics and decoding, fluency, vocabulary, and comprehension. These key ideas about SBRR in an adult education context may help teachers construct lesson/curriculum plans as well as guide them in goal-setting for their adult participants.</synopsis>
			<synopsis_cont></synopsis_cont>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Adult Reading Development</name>
			<file_type>PDF</file_type>
			<location>Resources\AdultEducation\Research\docs\ABE Cromley.pdf</location>
			<url>http://www.windwalker.com/evenstart/LPD/doc/document-center/ABE%20Cromley.pdf</url>
			<top_level_id>AE</top_level_id>
			<second_level_id>R</second_level_id>
			<tag>Jennifer Cromley, assessment</tag>
			<desc>This presentation describes how to assess where adult learners are in their literacy development.</desc>
			<synopsis>Jennifer Cromley describes 5 stages of literacy learning so that instructors can assess where their adult students are.  She also includes scores on several assessment instruments and what the score range for each level should be.  Strategies for teaching to each student level are also given.</synopsis>
			<synopsis_cont></synopsis_cont>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Phonological Awareness: Sample Weekly and Daily Lesson and Activity Plans</name>
			<file_type>Word</file_type>
			<location>Resources\EarlyChildhoodEducation\Worksheet\docs\Phonological Awareness Tools and Planning.doc</location>
			<url>http://www.windwalker.com/evenstart/LPD/doc/document-center/Phonological%20Awareness%20Tools%20and%20Planning.doc</url>
			<top_level_id>ECE</top_level_id>
			<second_level_id>W</second_level_id>
			<tag></tag>
			<desc>Teachers can use this lesson-planning framework to plan explicit small group instruction in phonological awareness and to integrate phonological instruction into weekly themes or units and daily classroom activities.</desc>
			<synopsis>In this sample plan, the teacher identified weekly learning goals for children and planned activities to provide children with practice in each of these goal areas on a daily basis. Notice how the phonological awareness goals and activities are planned at different skill levels on the developmental continuum. This enables the teacher to differentiate instruction for individual and small groups of children.</synopsis>
			<synopsis_cont></synopsis_cont>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Identifying Adult Goals, Goal-Setting and Tracking Progress Application Tool</name>
			<file_type>Word</file_type>
			<location>Resources\AdultEducation\Worksheet\docs\Unit 2 ABE Goal Setting tool.doc</location>
			<url>http://www.windwalker.com/evenstart/LPD/doc/document-center/Unit%202%20ABE%20Goal%20Setting%20tool.doc</url>
			<top_level_id>AE</top_level_id>
			<second_level_id>W</second_level_id>
			<tag>assessment</tag>
			<desc>This tracking tool provides information for adult education instructors to use in focusing instruction on adult goals.</desc>
			<synopsis>This process can help adult students set goals and continuously review progress toward their goals.  Included in the tool are a goal-setting and review process description, a goal-setting worksheet, and a monthly goal-tracking worksheet.</synopsis>
			<synopsis_cont></synopsis_cont>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Home-Based Activity Planner</name>
			<file_type>Word</file_type>
			<location>Resources\InteractiveLiteracyActivities\Worksheet\docs\Home-Based Activity Planner.doc</location>
			<url>http://www.windwalker.com/evenstart/LPD/doc/document-center/Home-Based%20Activity%20Planner.doc</url>
			<top_level_id>ILA</top_level_id>
			<second_level_id>W</second_level_id>
			<tag>culture</tag>
			<desc>This document describes the three aspects that home-based instructional services should contain.</desc>
			<synopsis>This document describes how to build rapport with families who are receiving home-based services, how to observe the family during the activity and discuss it with them afterward, and how to debrief them about the purpose of the activity afterwards.  Examples and questions follow each section.</synopsis>
			<synopsis_cont></synopsis_cont>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Interactive Literacy Activity Planner</name>
			<file_type>Word</file_type>
			<location>Resources\InteractiveLiteracyActivities\Worksheet\docs\ILA Planner.doc</location>
			<url>http://www.windwalker.com/evenstart/LPD/doc/document-center/ILA%20Planner.doc</url>
			<top_level_id>ILA</top_level_id>
			<second_level_id>W</second_level_id>
			<tag></tag>
			<desc>This document discusses how to plan interactive literacy activities that are research-based.</desc>
			<synopsis>This tool presents 5 steps to planning an interactive literacy activity.  The steps are: link goals and objectives, facilitate preparation, observe and model behaviors, promote and support positive beliefs, and discuss and debrief.  Each step is explained in detail, with examples and questions following.</synopsis>
			<synopsis_cont></synopsis_cont>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Engaging with Reading Through Interactive Read-Alouds</name>
			<file_type>PDF</file_type>
			<location>Resources\InteractiveLiteracyActivities\OnlineCourse\irtp\asset\class1\docs\Engaging with reading through interactive read alouds.pdf</location>
			<url>http://www.evenstartnetwork.net/irtp/asset/class1/docs/Engaging%20with%20reading%20through%20interactive%20read%20alouds.pdf</url>
			<top_level_id>ILA</top_level_id>
			<second_level_id>R</second_level_id>
			<tag>Shelby J. Barrentine</tag>
			<desc>This article presents an approach to reading aloud that provides a means of engaging students as they construct meaning and explore the reading process.</desc>
			<synopsis>Interactive read-alouds encourage children to verbally interact with the text, their peers, and the teacher.  The purpose of this article is two-fold: to shed light on read-aloud events as rich literacy demonstrations that engage children through dialogue and to share planning considerations to assist in implementing interactive read-aloud events.</synopsis>
			<synopsis_cont></synopsis_cont>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Planner for Reading with Toddlers</name>
			<file_type>PDF</file_type>
			<location>Resources\InteractiveLiteracyActivities\OnlineCourse\irtp\asset\class1\docs\Planner for Reading with Toddlers.pdf</location>
			<url>http://www.evenstartnetwork.net/irtp/asset/class1/docs/Planner%20for%20Reading%20with%20Toddlers.pdf</url>
			<top_level_id>ILA</top_level_id>
			<second_level_id>G</second_level_id>
			<tag></tag>
			<desc>This handout gives tips for preparing for an interactive literacy activity, conducting it, and reviewing it.</desc>
			<synopsis>This sheet of tips for interactive reading with toddlers discusses how to prepare, conduct, and review activities with familiar books, unfamiliar books, and books that the child has read many times before.</synopsis>
			<synopsis_cont></synopsis_cont>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Reading Tips for Parents of Toddlers</name>
			<file_type>PDF</file_type>
			<location>Resources\InteractiveLiteracyActivities\OnlineCourse\irtp\asset\class1\docs\Reading Tips for Parents of Toddlers.pdf</location>
			<url>http://www.evenstartnetwork.net/irtp/asset/class1/docs/Reading%20Tips%20for%20Parents%20of%20Toddlers.pdf</url>
			<top_level_id>ILA</top_level_id>
			<second_level_id>G</second_level_id>
			<tag>play</tag>
			<desc>This sheet provides tips to parents for reading with their toddlers.</desc>
			<synopsis>These tips are meant to encourage continued language development and interest in books and reading by keeping learning lively and engaging.
Everyday experiences are full of opportunities to engage in conversation and develop language skills. The tips offer some fun ways parents can help
their children become happy and confident readers.
			</synopsis>
			<synopsis_cont></synopsis_cont>
		</item>
		<!-- 
		<item>
			<name>Interactive Reading with Toddlers and Preschoolers: Class 1</name>
			<file_type>PDF</file_type>
			<location>Resources\InteractiveLiteracyActivities\OnlineCourse\irtp\asset\class1\docs\Class 1 Handouts.pdf</location>
			<url>http://www.evenstartnetwork.net/irtp/asset/class1/docs/Class%201%20Handouts.pdf</url>
			<top_level_id>ILA</top_level_id>
			<second_level_id>R</second_level_id>
			<tag>Shelley Gray</tag>
			<desc>This presentation gives an overview of interactive reading.</desc>
			<synopsis>The presentation starts by defining interactive reading, then discussing its usefulness.  Some resources for research on interactive reading are also given.  Shelley Gray also gives pointers on the parts of a narrative and on the benefits of using different kinds of books with children.</synopsis>
			<synopsis_cont></synopsis_cont>
		</item> 
		-->
		<item>
			<name>A Book of One's Own</name>
			<file_type>PDF</file_type>
			<location>Resources\InteractiveLiteracyActivities\OnlineCourse\irtp\asset\class2\docs\CELLprac_Book_OnesOwn.pdf</location>
			<url>http://www.evenstartnetwork.net/irtp/asset/class2/docs/CELLprac_Book_OnesOwn.pdf</url>
			<top_level_id>ILA</top_level_id>
			<second_level_id>G</second_level_id>
			<tag>play</tag>
			<desc>This pamphlet gives advice to parents on incorporating literacy learning into a toddler's everyday activities.</desc>
			<synopsis>Holding and using books, crayons, and other reading and writing materials helps toddlers build
literacy skills they will use throughout their lives. In this guide you&#x2019;ll find ideas for fun ways to enrich
your child&#x2019;s home life with everyday literacy learning. Case studies of 3 children are also included.
			</synopsis>
			<synopsis_cont></synopsis_cont>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Determinants of Acquisition Order in Wh-Questions: Re-evaluating the Role of Caregiver Speech</name>
			<file_type>PDF</file_type>
			<location>Resources\InteractiveLiteracyActivities\OnlineCourse\irtp\asset\class2\docs\Determinants of acquisition order in wh-questions.pdf</location>
			<url>http://www.evenstartnetwork.net/irtp/asset/class2/docs/Determinants%20of%20acquisition%20order%20in%20wh-questions.pdf</url>
			<top_level_id>ECE</top_level_id>
			<second_level_id>R</second_level_id>
			<tag>Caroline F. Rowland, Julian M. Pine, Elena V. M. Lieven, Anna L. Theakston</tag>
			<desc>This article describes a study meant to determine what part of language acquisition has the most influence on a child's use of wh- questions (what, why, where).</desc>
			<synopsis>In the study presented here, over 300 hours of
naturalistic data from twelve two- to three-year-old children and their mothers were analysed in order to assess the relative contribution of complexity and input frequency to wh-question acquisition. The
analyses revealed, first, that the acquisition order of wh-questions could be predicted successfully from the frequency with which particular wh-words and verbs occurred in the children&#x2019;s input and, second, that syntactic and semantic complexity did not reliably predict acquisition once input frequency was taken into account. The results are interpreted in terms of a constructivist view of language acquisition.
			</synopsis>
			<synopsis_cont></synopsis_cont>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Teaching Wh-Questions to English Language Learners: A Review of Current Research with Practical Suggestions</name>
			<file_type>PDF</file_type>
			<location>Resources\InteractiveLiteracyActivities\OnlineCourse\irtp\asset\class2\docs\wh questions nonnative speakers.pdf</location>
			<url>http://www.evenstartnetwork.net/irtp/asset/class2/docs/wh%20questions%20nonnative%20speakers.pdf</url>
			<top_level_id>ECE</top_level_id>
			<second_level_id>R</second_level_id>
			<tag>Nathan Fellman, ESL, ELL</tag>
			<desc>The purpose of this
research is to develop practical ways of teaching wh- questions (what, why where) as lexical units in order to foster
language production and expansion at the very earliest stages of English acquisition.
			</desc>
			<synopsis>Understanding that it is beneficial to teach wh-questions to beginning ELLs even before
those students have the knowledge and skills to grammatically comprehend them, we must seek
to discover the best methods of teaching wh-questions holophrastically in the very earliest stages
of language development. An important step in understanding these best methods is to examine
the differences among wh-questions, and the difficulties learners experience in the sequence of
acquiring wh-questions.  This is what this paper seeks to do.
			</synopsis>
			<synopsis_cont></synopsis_cont>
		</item>
		<!--
		<item>
			<name>Interactive Reading with Toddlers and Preschoolers: Class 2</name>
			<file_type>PDF</file_type>
			<location>Resources\InteractiveLiteracyActivities\OnlineCourse\irtp\asset\class2\docs\Class 2 Handouts.pdf</location>
			<url>http://www.evenstartnetwork.net/irtp/asset/class2/docs/Class%202%20Handouts.pdf</url>
			<top_level_id>ILA</top_level_id>
			<second_level_id>G</second_level_id>
			<tag>play, ESL, Shelley Gray, ELL</tag>
			<desc>This presentation gives ways to keep children engaged in interactive reading time.</desc>
			<synopsis>This presentation gives strategies on how to keep children's attention focused during interactive reading time. Shelley Gray also gives examples of how to elaborate on, ask questions about, and comment on what is being read.</synopsis>
			<synopsis_cont></synopsis_cont>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Interactive Reading Planning Sheet</name>
			<file_type>PDF</file_type>
			<location>Resources\InteractiveLiteracyActivities\OnlineCourse\irtp\asset\class3\docs\Interactive Reading Planning Sheet.pdf</location>
			<url>http://www.evenstartnetwork.net/irtp/asset/class3/docs/Interactive%20Reading%20Planning%20Sheet.pdf</url>
			<top_level_id>ILA</top_level_id>
			<second_level_id>W</second_level_id>
			<tag></tag>
			<desc>This planner helps a teacher plan multiple readings of a book during interactive reading time.</desc>
			<synopsis>This interactive reading planner allows a teacher to plan to read one book multiple times and multiple ways with children over time.  For each reading, the objective, vocabulary, and materials should be noted for the preparation stage of the reading, and notes on what should happen during each of the other stages (introduction, during, and after) should be made.</synopsis>
			<synopsis_cont></synopsis_cont>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Interactive Reading Planning Sheet Examples</name>
			<file_type>PDF</file_type>
			<location>Resources\InteractiveLiteracyActivities\OnlineCourse\irtp\asset\class3\docs\Interactive Reading Planning Sheet Examples.pdf</location>
			<url>http://www.evenstartnetwork.net/irtp/asset/class3/docs/Interactive%20Reading%20Planning%20Sheet%20Examples.pdf</url>
			<top_level_id>ILA</top_level_id>
			<second_level_id>W</second_level_id>
			<tag></tag>
			<desc>This sheet provides an example of how to plan interactive reading time.</desc>
			<synopsis>This planner has been filled in with details of an example book to show how to plan the objective, vocabulary, and materials for each time a book is read, along with what should happen during the book's introduction, during the reading, and afterwards.</synopsis>
			<synopsis_cont></synopsis_cont>
		</item>
		-->
		<item>
			<name>Planner for Interactive Reading with Preschoolers Examples</name>
			<file_type>PDF</file_type>
			<location>Resources\InteractiveLiteracyActivities\OnlineCourse\irtp\asset\class3\docs\Planner for Interactive Reading with Preschoolers.pdf</location>
			<url>http://www.evenstartnetwork.net/irtp/asset/class3/docs/Planner%20for%20Interactive%20Reading%20with%20Preschoolers.pdf</url>
			<top_level_id>ILA</top_level_id>
			<second_level_id>W</second_level_id>
			<tag></tag>
			<desc>This planning sheet has been filled in with tips for how to structure interactive reading time.</desc>
			<synopsis>This planner has been filled in with strategies for structuring interactive reading time.  This includes preparing the materials and thinking about the goal of the lesson, introducing and reading the book, and debriefing afterwards.</synopsis>
			<synopsis_cont></synopsis_cont>
		</item>
		<!--
		<item>
			<name>Interactive Reading Planner for Bark, George</name>
			<file_type>PDF</file_type>
			<location>Resources\InteractiveLiteracyActivities\OnlineCourse\irtp\asset\class3\docs\Interactive Reading Planning Sheet for Bark, George.pdf</location>
			<url>http://www.evenstartnetwork.net/irtp/asset/class3/docs/Interactive%20Reading%20Planning%20Sheet%20for%20Bark,%20George.pdf</url>
			<top_level_id>ILA</top_level_id>
			<second_level_id>W</second_level_id>
			<tag></tag>
			<desc>This interactive reading planner has been completed for the book Bark, George.</desc>
			<synopsis>This planner has been completed with details on preparing for and conducting an interactive reading session on the book Bark, George. The way the lesson would evolve over multiple readings is also included.</synopsis>
			<synopsis_cont></synopsis_cont>
		</item>
		-->
		<item>
			<name>Planner for Interactive Reading for Dr. DeSoto</name>
			<file_type>PDF</file_type>
			<location>Resources\InteractiveLiteracyActivities\OnlineCourse\irtp\asset\class3\docs\Planner for Interactive Reading for Dr. DeSoto.pdf</location>
			<url>http://www.evenstartnetwork.net/irtp/asset/class3/docs/Planner%20for%20Interactive%20Reading%20for%20Dr.%20DeSoto.pdf</url>
			<top_level_id>ILA</top_level_id>
			<second_level_id>W</second_level_id>
			<tag></tag>
			<desc>This interactive reading planner has been completed for the book Dr. DeSoto.</desc>
			<synopsis>This planner has been completed with details on preparing for and conducting an interactive reading session on the book Dr. DeSoto. The way the lesson would evolve over multiple readings is also included.</synopsis>
			<synopsis_cont></synopsis_cont>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Planner for Interactive Reading for Floating in Space</name>
			<file_type>pdf</file_type>
			<location>Resources\InteractiveLiteracyActivities\OnlineCourse\irtp\asset\class3\docs\Planner for Interactive Reading for Floating in Space.pdf</location>
			<url>http://www.evenstartnetwork.net/irtp/asset/class3/docs/Planner%20for%20Interactive%20Reading%20for%20Floating%20in%20Space.pdf</url>
			<top_level_id>ILA</top_level_id>
			<second_level_id>W</second_level_id>
			<tag></tag>
			<desc>This interactive reading planner has been completed for the book Floating in Space.</desc>
			<synopsis>This planner has been completed with details on preparing for and conducting an interactive reading session on the book Floating in Space. The way the lesson would evolve over multiple readings is also included.</synopsis>
			<synopsis_cont></synopsis_cont>
		</item>
		<!--
		<item>
			<name>Interactive Reading with Toddlers and Preschoolers: Class 3</name>
			<file_type>PDF</file_type>
			<location>Resources\InteractiveLiteracyActivities\OnlineCourse\irtp\asset\class3\docs\Class 3 handouts.pdf</location>
			<url>http://www.evenstartnetwork.net/irtp/asset/class3/docs/Class%203%20handouts.pdf</url>
			<top_level_id>ILA</top_level_id>
			<second_level_id>G</second_level_id>
			<tag>Shelley Gray</tag>
			<desc>This presentation describes how to prepare for an interactive reading lesson, and what to do during the first reading of a book.</desc>
			<synopsis>This presentation discusses how to create an inviting, literate environment in which to have interactive reading time.  It also describes how to plan an interactive reading lesson, focusing on the first time the children are reading the book.</synopsis>
			<synopsis_cont></synopsis_cont>
		</item>
		-->
		<item>
			<name>Planner for Interactive Reading for Click Clack Moo Cows that Type</name>
			<file_type>PDF</file_type>
			<location>Resources\InteractiveLiteracyActivities\OnlineCourse\irtp\asset\class4\docs\Planner for Interactive Reading for Click Clack Moo Cows that Type.pdf</location>
			<url>http://www.evenstartnetwork.net/irtp/asset/class4/docs/Planner%20for%20Interactive%20Reading%20for%20Click%20Clack%20Moo%20Cows%20that%20Type.pdf</url>
			<top_level_id>ILA</top_level_id>
			<second_level_id>W</second_level_id>
			<tag></tag>
			<desc>This interactive reading planner has been completed for the book Click Clack Moo Cows That Type.</desc>
			<synopsis>This planner has been completed with details on preparing for and conducting an interactive reading session on the book Click Clack Moo Cows That Type. The way the lesson would evolve over multiple readings is also included.</synopsis>
			<synopsis_cont></synopsis_cont>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Planner for Interactive Reading for The Three Billy Goats Gruff</name>
			<file_type>PDF</file_type>
			<location>Resources\InteractiveLiteracyActivities\OnlineCourse\irtp\asset\class4\docs\Planner for Interactive Reading for The Three Billy Goats Gruff.pdf</location>
			<url>http://www.evenstartnetwork.net/irtp/asset/class4/docs/Planner%20for%20Interactive%20Reading%20for%20The%20Three%20Billy%20Goats%20Gruff.pdf</url>
			<top_level_id>ILA</top_level_id>
			<second_level_id>W</second_level_id>
			<tag></tag>
			<desc>This interactive reading planner has been completed for the book The Three Billy Goats Gruff.</desc>
			<synopsis>This planner has been completed with details on preparing for and conducting an interactive reading session on the book The Three Billy Goats Gruff. The way the lesson would evolve over multiple readings is also included.</synopsis>
			<synopsis_cont></synopsis_cont>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Planner for Interactive Reading for Wild About Books</name>
			<file_type>PDF</file_type>
			<location>Resources\InteractiveLiteracyActivities\OnlineCourse\irtp\asset\class4\docs\Planner for Interactive Reading for Wild About Books.pdf</location>
			<url>http://www.evenstartnetwork.net/irtp/asset/class4/docs/Planner%20for%20Interactive%20Reading%20for%20Wild%20About%20Books.pdf</url>
			<top_level_id>ILA</top_level_id>
			<second_level_id>W</second_level_id>
			<tag></tag>
			<desc>This interactive reading planner has been completed for the book Wild About Books.</desc>
			<synopsis>This planner has been completed with details on preparing for and conducting an interactive reading session on the book Wild About Books. The way the lesson would evolve over multiple readings is also included.</synopsis>
			<synopsis_cont></synopsis_cont>
		</item>
		<!-- 
		<item>
			<name>Interactive Reading with Toddlers and Preschoolers: Class 4</name>
			<file_type>PDF</file_type>
			<location>Resources\InteractiveLiteracyActivities\OnlineCourse\irtp\asset\class4\docs\Class 4 Handouts.pdf</location>
			<url>http://www.evenstartnetwork.net/irtp/asset/class4/docs/Class%204%20Handouts.pdf</url>
			<top_level_id>ILA</top_level_id>
			<second_level_id>G</second_level_id>
			<tag>Shelley Gray, scaffolding</tag>
			<desc>This presentation discusses how to alter interactive reading time when the children are reading the book for the second time.</desc>
			<synopsis>This presentation provides strategies on how to plan for a second interactive reading of a book.  Planning is divided into preparation, introductory, beginning, and after stages.  Scaffolding is discussed in the after section as a way to support children's learning.</synopsis>
			<synopsis_cont></synopsis_cont>
		</item>
		-->
		<item>
			<name>Planner for Interactive Reading for Chicka Chicka Boom Boom</name>
			<file_type>PDF</file_type>
			<location>Resources\InteractiveLiteracyActivities\OnlineCourse\irtp\asset\class5\docs\Planner for Interactive Reading for Chicka Chicka Boom Boom.pdf</location>
			<url>http://www.evenstartnetwork.net/irtp/asset/class5/docs/Planner%20for%20Interactive%20Reading%20for%20Chicka%20Chicka%20Boom%20Boom.pdf</url>
			<top_level_id>ILA</top_level_id>
			<second_level_id>W</second_level_id>
			<tag></tag>
			<desc>This interactive reading planner has been completed for the book Chicka Chicka Boom Boom.</desc>
			<synopsis>This planner has been completed with details on preparing for and conducting an interactive reading session on the book Chicka Chicka Boom Boom. The way the lesson would evolve over multiple readings is also included.</synopsis>
			<synopsis_cont></synopsis_cont>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Planner for Interactive Reading for the Post Office Book</name>
			<file_type>pdf</file_type>
			<location>Resources\InteractiveLiteracyActivities\OnlineCourse\irtp\asset\class5\docs\Planner for Interactive Reading for The Post Office Book.pdf</location>
			<url>http://www.evenstartnetwork.net/irtp/asset/class5/docs/Planner%20for%20Interactive%20Reading%20for%20The%20Post%20Office%20Book.pdf</url>
			<top_level_id>ILA</top_level_id>
			<second_level_id>W</second_level_id>
			<tag></tag>
			<desc>This interactive reading planner has been completed for the book The Post Office Book.</desc>
			<synopsis>This planner has been completed with details on preparing for and conducting an interactive reading session on the book The Post Office Book. The way the lesson would evolve over multiple readings is also included.</synopsis>
			<synopsis_cont></synopsis_cont>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Providing Leadership Part 1</name>
			<file_type>URL/Flash</file_type>
			<location>Resources\EarlyChildhoodEducation\Guidelines\video\1_jj_01\1_jj_01.html</location>
			<url>http://www.evenstartnetwork.net/2008meeting/videos/janisJackson/1_providingLeadership/1_jj_01/1_jj_01.html</url>
			<top_level_id>ECE</top_level_id>
			<second_level_id>G</second_level_id>
			<tag>Janice Jackson</tag>
			<desc>This is the first part of Dr. Janice Jackson's four-part presentation on how to effect leadership and organizational change in public schools and  family literacy programs.</desc>
			<synopsis>In this section of her presentation, after giving a history of her work, Dr. Jackson discusses how early childhood educators should look at the long-term purpose of their work as setting the foundation for a child's educational career. She talks about focusing on what is best for the child in whatever you do.</synopsis>
			<synopsis_cont></synopsis_cont>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Providing Leadership Part 2</name>
			<file_type>URL/Flash</file_type>
			<location>Resources\EarlyChildhoodEducation\Guidelines\video\1_jj_02\1_jj_02.html</location>
			<url>http://www.evenstartnetwork.net/2008meeting/videos/janisJackson/1_providingLeadership/1_jj_02/1_jj_02.html</url>
			<top_level_id>ECE</top_level_id>
			<second_level_id>G</second_level_id>
			<tag>Janice Jackson</tag>
			<desc>This is the second part of Dr. Janice Jackson's four-part presentation on how to effect leadership and organizational change in public schools and  family literacy programs.</desc>
			<synopsis>Jackson begins this part of her presentation by discussing accountability, program assessment, and research. She also discusses the importance of early childhood education and the problem of many children starting elementary school unable to read. She then talks about the challenge of educating U.S. students so they are internationally competitive.</synopsis>
			<synopsis_cont></synopsis_cont>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Providing Leadership Part 3</name>
			<file_type>URL/Flash</file_type>
			<location>Resources\EarlyChildhoodEducation\Guidelines\video\1_jj_03\1_jj_03.html</location>
			<url>http://www.evenstartnetwork.net/2008meeting/videos/janisJackson/1_providingLeadership/1_jj_03/1_jj_03.html</url>
			<top_level_id>ECE</top_level_id>
			<second_level_id>G</second_level_id>
			<tag>Janice Jackson</tag>
			<desc>This is the third part of Dr. Janice Jackson's four-part presentation on how to effect leadership and organizational change in public schools and  family literacy programs.</desc>
			<synopsis>Jackson begins this section talking about working with varying values in different types of communities to ensure that kids succeed. She also discusses how to ensure that kids enjoy life while they are learning. She then describes skills that kids need to develop for the 21st century workforce.</synopsis>
			<synopsis_cont></synopsis_cont>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Providing Leadership Part 4</name>
			<file_type>URL/Flash</file_type>
			<location>Resources\EarlyChildhoodEducation\Guidelines\video\1_jj_04\1_jj_04.html</location>
			<url>http://www.evenstartnetwork.net/2008meeting/videos/janisJackson/1_providingLeadership/1_jj_04/1_jj_04.html</url>
			<top_level_id>ECE</top_level_id>
			<second_level_id>G</second_level_id>
			<tag>Janice Jackson</tag>
			<desc>This is the fourth part of Dr. Janice Jackson's four-part presentation on how to effect leadership and organizational change in public schools and  family literacy programs.</desc>
			<synopsis>In this section of her presentation, Jackson continues taking about globalization and preparing children for the future. She then switches to talking about the aspects and meanings of leadership, particularly within educational organizations. She then gets her listeners thinking about what they think federal agencies of the future should ideally look like.</synopsis>
			<synopsis_cont></synopsis_cont>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Teaching ESL Literacy to Adults: A Guide for Adult Literacy Teachers</name>
			<file_type>PDF</file_type>
			<location>Resources\AdultEducation\Guidelines\docs\1.pdf</location>
			<url>http://www.evenstartnetwork.net/LiteracyDevelopment/website/Resources\/1.pdf</url>
			<top_level_id>AE</top_level_id>
			<second_level_id>G</second_level_id>
			<tag>ESL, ELL, Judy Colman, Jill Schiffmann, assessment, Australia</tag>
			<desc>This guide was designed to help teachers respond appropriately to the language and literacy needs of adults of a non-English-speaking background.</desc>
			<synopsis>This guide was designed for teachers in rural Australia but its principles can be applied anywhere.  One section addresses the general topics of language learning and literacy development in a second language, and the relationship between oral and written language.  The next section discusses literacy skills assessment procedures and principles.  Strategies for applying this information to the classroom curriculum are then presented. Further resources, a glossary, and forms for first language literacy assessment in multiple languages are appended.</synopsis>
			<synopsis_cont></synopsis_cont>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>What Beginning Teachers and Tutors of Adult English Language Learners Need to Know</name>
			<file_type>PDF</file_type>
			<location>Resources\AdultEducation\Guidelines\docs\2.pdf</location>
			<url>http://www.evenstartnetwork.net/LiteracyDevelopment/website/Resources\/2.pdf</url>
			<top_level_id>AE</top_level_id>
			<second_level_id>G</second_level_id>
			<tag>ESL, ELL</tag>
			<desc>This resource
collection provides materials about second language acquisition, language and culture,
instructional approaches that support language development, curricula, and professional
development.
			</desc>
			<synopsis>This article describes the rise in ELLs in the United States in recent years and its impact on new teachers.  Then experienced ESL teachers give advice about what new ESL teachers should know to run successful second language classrooms.  Advice is given on lesson planning, teacher-student interaction, student seating, etc.  Further resources such as research, organizations, and curricula are also described.</synopsis>
			<synopsis_cont></synopsis_cont>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Teaching Low-Level Adult ESL Learners</name>
			<file_type>PDF</file_type>
			<location>Resources\AdultEducation\Guidelines\docs\3.pdf</location>
			<url>http://www.evenstartnetwork.net/LiteracyDevelopment/website/Resources\/3.pdf</url>
			<top_level_id>AE</top_level_id>
			<second_level_id>G</second_level_id>
			<tag>ESL, ELL, Grace Massey Holt</tag>
			<desc>This article provides strategies for teaching English language learners who do not have literacy in their first language.</desc>
			<synopsis>This digest provides information on how to identify and assess the instructional needs of adults learners to become literate in a second language. It also discusses general techniques that facilitate instruction for these learners, provides a sample procedure for combining some of these techniques, and describes classroom materials appropriate for low-level adult ESL learners.</synopsis>
			<synopsis_cont></synopsis_cont>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Working with Literacy-Level Adult English Language Learners</name>
			<file_type>PDF</file_type>
			<location>Resources\AdultEducation\Guidelines\docs\4.pdf</location>
			<url>http://www.evenstartnetwork.net/LiteracyDevelopment/website/Resources\/4.pdf</url>
			<top_level_id>AE</top_level_id>
			<second_level_id>G</second_level_id>
			<tag>ESL, ELL, assessment, MaryAnn Cunningham Florez, Lynda Terrill</tag>
			<desc>This paper describes literacy-level learners and the skills they need to develop.</desc>
			<synopsis>This article describes the needs of English language learners who do not have literacy in their first language. It describes the different levels of literacy that a teacher may encounter and the skills the ELLs need to acquire, beyond reading and language skills.  The paper then discusses effective practices for literacy-level classes and gives examples of activities and techniques that support these practices.</synopsis>
			<synopsis_cont></synopsis_cont>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Second Language Acquisition in Adults: From Research to Practice</name>
			<file_type>PDF</file_type>
			<location>Resources\AdultEducation\Research\docs\5.pdf</location>
			<url>http://www.evenstartnetwork.net/LiteracyDevelopment/website/Resources\/5.pdf</url>
			<top_level_id>AE</top_level_id>
			<second_level_id>R</second_level_id>
			<tag>ESL, ELL, Donna Moss, Lauren Ross-Feldman</tag>
			<desc>This paper discusses how second language acquisition research can be used to enhance language instruction.</desc>
			<synopsis>Second language acquisition (SLA) is the study of how second languages are learned and the factors that influence the process. The purpose of this Q&amp;A is to show how SLA research can inform adult ESL instruction. Research in three areas of SLA are discussed: (1) the effect of learner motivation, (2) the role of interaction, and (3) the role of vocabulary. The research presented here includes experimental, correlational, and descriptive studies, as well as theoretical articles that analyze the results of other research.</synopsis>
			<synopsis_cont></synopsis_cont>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Beginning to Work with Adult English Language Learners: Some Considerations</name>
			<file_type>PDF</file_type>
			<location>Resources\AdultEducation\Guidelines\docs\6.pdf</location>
			<url>http://www.evenstartnetwork.net/LiteracyDevelopment/website/Resources\/6.pdf</url>
			<top_level_id>AE</top_level_id>
			<second_level_id>G</second_level_id>
			<tag>ESL, ELL, assessment, MaryAnn Cunningham Florez</tag>
			<desc>This paper provides a Q&amp;A on what teachers who are beginning to work with adult English language learners need
to know.
			</desc>
			<synopsis>This Q&amp;A discusses recommendations in four areas: application of principles of adult learning in ESL contexts, second language acquisition, culture and working with multicultural groups, and instructional approaches that support language development in adults. It is not intended to be comprehensive. Rather, it gives teachers an overview of important points, suggests basic strategies to use, and provides resources to consult for further information.</synopsis>
			<synopsis_cont></synopsis_cont>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Philosophies and Approaches in Adult ESL Literacy Instruction</name>
			<file_type>PDF</file_type>
			<location>Resources\AdultEducation\Guidelines\docs\7.pdf</location>
			<url>http://www.evenstartnetwork.net/LiteracyDevelopment/website/Resources\/7.pdf</url>
			<top_level_id>AE</top_level_id>
			<second_level_id>G</second_level_id>
			<tag>ESL, ELL, Joy Peyton, JoAnn Crandall</tag>
			<desc>This digest gives an overview of five approaches used in adult ESL instruction.</desc>
			<synopsis>There are five approaches described in this article. They represent a range of practices used in native language and biliteracy programs as well as in ESL classes, with learners whose literacy ranges from limited to advanced.  The five approaches are: Freirean or participatory education, whole language, language experience approach, learner writing and publishing, and competency-based education.</synopsis>
			<synopsis_cont></synopsis_cont>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Teaching Multilevel Adult ESL Classes</name>
			<file_type>PDF</file_type>
			<location>Resources\AdultEducation\Guidelines\docs\8.pdf</location>
			<url>http://www.evenstartnetwork.net/LiteracyDevelopment/website/Resources\/8.pdf</url>
			<top_level_id>AE</top_level_id>
			<second_level_id>G</second_level_id>
			<tag>ESL, ELL, assessment, Cathy C. Shank, Lynda Terrill</tag>
			<desc>This digest recommends ways to choose and organize content for multilevel ESL classes.</desc>
			<synopsis>This article explains various tactics for teaching ESL classess composed of students with different levels of literacy.  It explains grouping strategies; discusses a self-access component, independent work for individual learners; and offers suggestions for managing the classes.</synopsis>
			<synopsis_cont></synopsis_cont>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>The Language Experience Approach and Adult Learners</name>
			<file_type>PDF</file_type>
			<location>Resources\AdultEducation\Guidelines\docs\9.pdf</location>
			<url>http://www.evenstartnetwork.net/LiteracyDevelopment/website/Resources\/9.pdf</url>
			<top_level_id>AE</top_level_id>
			<second_level_id>G</second_level_id>
			<tag>ESL, ELL, Marcia Taylor</tag>
			<desc>This article describes the language experience approach (LEA), which is a whole language approach that promotes reading and writing through the use of personal experiences and oral language.</desc>
			<synopsis>LEA, described in this article, can be used in tutorial or classroom settings with homogeneous or heterogeneous groups of learners. Beginning literacy learners relate their experiences to a teacher or aide, who transcribes them. These transcriptions are then used as the basis for other reading and writing activities.  Features of LEA include: all materials are learner-generated; all communication skills--reading, writing, listening, and speaking--are integrated; the difficulty of vocabulary and grammar are determined by the learner's own language use; and learning and teaching are personalized, communicative, and creative.</synopsis>
			<synopsis_cont></synopsis_cont>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Trauma and the English Language Learner</name>
			<file_type>PDF</file_type>
			<location>Resources\AdultEducation\Guidelines\docs\10.pdf</location>
			<url>http://www.evenstartnetwork.net/LiteracyDevelopment/website/Resources\/10.pdf</url>
			<top_level_id>AE</top_level_id>
			<second_level_id>G</second_level_id>
			<tag>ESL, ELL, Janet Isserlis</tag>
			<desc>This article discusses trauma and abuse in the immigrant community and how those experiences impact the way adult ELLs should be taught.</desc>
			<synopsis>Acknowledgement of the prevalence of violence generally, and of that experienced by those in the adult ESL and literacy community specifically, is critical to the development of instructional approaches that make classrooms safer and learning more possible for adult immigrant learners. This digest describes trauma and abuse in immigrant communities, discusses the effects of trauma on learning, and suggests ways in which practitioners can modify their practice to facilitate learning among victims of trauma and violence.</synopsis>
			<synopsis_cont></synopsis_cont>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Cross-Cultural Issues in Adult ESL Classrooms</name>
			<file_type>PDF</file_type>
			<location>Resources\AdultEducation\Guidelines\docs\11.pdf</location>
			<url>http://www.evenstartnetwork.net/LiteracyDevelopment/website/Resources\/11.pdf</url>
			<top_level_id>AE</top_level_id>
			<second_level_id>G</second_level_id>
			<tag>ESL, ELL, culture, Mary McGroarty</tag>
			<desc>This digest identifies some of the cultural factors that can influence learner and teacher behavior during classroom ESL literacy instruction.</desc>
			<synopsis>Adult ESL classes in the United States serve as a meeting place for learners of many and often disparate cultural backgrounds. The ESL class serves the crucial function of cultural as well as linguistic orientation.  This article discusses ways that understanding cultural factors can inform instruction in a positive way.</synopsis>
			<synopsis_cont></synopsis_cont>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Effective Instruction for Adult ESL Literacy Students: Findings from the What Works Study</name>
			<file_type>PDF</file_type>
			<location>Resources\AdultEducation\Research\docs\12.pdf</location>
			<url>http://www.evenstartnetwork.net/LiteracyDevelopment/website/Resources\/12.pdf</url>
			<top_level_id>AE</top_level_id>
			<second_level_id>R</second_level_id>
			<tag>ESL, ELL, assessment, Larry Condelli</tag>
			<desc>This article describes findings from the &#x201C;What Works&#x201D; Study for Adult ESL Literacy Students, the purpose of which was to identify ways in which adult ESL programs can provide effective instruction to improve the English language and literacy skills of these students.</desc>
			<synopsis>The What Works study described here was the first of its kind. Since the study did find evidence about the instructional and program approaches that make a difference, it provides policy makers with information to make decisions about programs and guides practitioners as they design and implement the education they provide to ESL literacy adults.  The study focused on Adult English-as-a-second-language (ESL) literacy students that lack literacy skills in their native language as well as English communication skills.</synopsis>
			<synopsis_cont></synopsis_cont>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Canadian Language Benchmarks 2000: ESL for Literacy Learners</name>
			<file_type>PDF</file_type>
			<location>Resources\AdultEducation\Guidelines\docs\13.pdf</location>
			<url>http://www.evenstartnetwork.net/LiteracyDevelopment/website/Resources\/13.pdf</url>
			<top_level_id>AE</top_level_id>
			<second_level_id>G</second_level_id>
			<tag>ESL, ELL, Canada, standards, assessment</tag>
			<desc>These benchmarks are descriptions of what ESL students are able to do at various stages stages of their development.</desc>
			<synopsis>The ESL Literacy Benchmarks lay out the progression of reading, writing, and numeracy skills for ESL adults who have little or no literacy skills in their first language.  The document is also useful with ESL students who are literate in a non-Roman alphabet language and need to learn reading and writing basics in English.  The benchmarks are not a curriculum, nor are they a test; however, they can be used to inform the development of both.  They are divided into a pre-reading and writing phase, called the Foundation Phase, followed by Phases I-III.</synopsis>
			<synopsis_cont></synopsis_cont>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Techniques for Teaching Beginning-Level Reading to Adults</name>
			<file_type>PDF</file_type>
			<location>Resources\AdultEducation\Research\docs\AE ESL course Hager article.pdf</location>
			<url>P:\225 evenstart\working\Website docs\AE ESL course Hager article.pdf</url>
			<top_level_id>AE</top_level_id>
			<second_level_id>R</second_level_id>
			<tag>ESL, ELL, Ashley Hager, special education</tag>
			<desc>This article attempts to
determine how reading acquisition research conducted with children can be applied to teaching reading to adults.
			</desc>
			<synopsis>In this article Ashley Hagar describes her ESL classroom and the techniques she uses with her students.  Topics covered include: phonological awareness, word analysis, special, oral reading, sight word reading, and comprehension.  Links are made to research in early childhood education that is applicable to adult learners as well.</synopsis>
			<synopsis_cont></synopsis_cont>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Beginning ESOL Learners' Advice to Their Teachers</name>
			<file_type>PDF</file_type>
			<location>Resources\AdultEducation\Guidelines\docs\AE ESL course Florez article.pdf</location>
			<url>P:\225 evenstart\working\Website docs\AE ESL course Florez article.pdf</url>
			<top_level_id>AE</top_level_id>
			<second_level_id>G</second_level_id>
			<tag>ESL, ELL, MaryAnn Cunningham Florez</tag>
			<desc>This article provides advice from students for new ESL teachers.</desc>
			<synopsis>Florez conducted focus groups in Spanish with students at her school in order to find out what, based on their experience, was most important in ESL classrooms.  This article summarizes the most frequent comments.  Ideas for how to elicit your own students' feedback are also included.</synopsis>
			<synopsis_cont></synopsis_cont>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Using a Multisensory Approach to Help Struggling Adult Learners</name>
			<file_type>PDF</file_type>
			<location>Resources\AdultEducation\TeachingActivity\docs\AE ESL course Geertz article.pdf</location>
			<url>P:\225 evenstart\working\Website docs\AE ESL course Geertz article.pdf</url>
			<top_level_id>AE</top_level_id>
			<second_level_id>TA</second_level_id>
			<tag>ESL, ELL, Gladys Geertz</tag>
			<desc>This article provides a sample multisensory lesson to use with low-literacy adults.</desc>
			<synopsis>In a multisensory adult education lesson, the instructor provides instruction, guides the students through a successful learning experience, and then reinforces this successful learning experience.  Geertz describes a sample lesson and how it leads low-literacy adults to success.</synopsis>
			<synopsis_cont></synopsis_cont>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Teaching Reading to First-Level Adults: Emerging Trends in Research and Practice</name>
			<file_type>PDF</file_type>
			<location>Resources\AdultEducation\Research\docs\AE ESL course Alamprese article.pdf</location>
			<url>P:\225 evenstart\working\Website docs\AE ESL course Alamprese article.pdf</url>
			<top_level_id>AE</top_level_id>
			<second_level_id>R</second_level_id>
			<tag>ESL, ELL, Judith A. Alamprese, culture</tag>
			<desc>This article describes the beginnings of a study on the effectiveness of adult basic education programs.</desc>
			<synopsis>The study described here is meant to fill in the gaps in adult literacy research and to see what sort of instruction works best with adults.  The study looks at instruction, but also at other factors that may affect a student's performance: cultural factors, staff qualifications, family problems, etc. The trends in instruction that are being documented in the study offer some insight into current reading instructional practices that are of interest to teachers serving first-level learners and who are interested in offering group-based instruction.</synopsis>
			<synopsis_cont></synopsis_cont>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Parents' Support for Children's Literacy</name>
			<file_type>PPT</file_type>
			<location>Resources\ParentingEducation\Guidelines\docs\Parent Support for Children's Literacy.ppt</location>
			<url>P:\225 evenstart\working\2011 Meeting Materials\Tribal\Parent Support for Children's Literacy.ppt</url>
			<top_level_id>PE</top_level_id>
			<second_level_id>G</second_level_id>
			<tag>Cynthia Harvell</tag>
			<desc>This presentation by Cynthia Harvell discusses how to support parents to take a more effective role in their children's education.</desc>
			<synopsis>This presentation begins by discussing how to build a parent's sense of self-efficacy so he or she has a positive influence on the child's education. It also presents rating scales to pinpoint each parent's skill level on a variety of topics. It concludes with a discussion on how to plan interactive literacy activities so that parents get the most out of them.</synopsis>
			<synopsis_cont></synopsis_cont>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Scale for Rating Parent's Support for Children's Literacy in the Home Environment</name>
			<file_type>PDF</file_type>
			<location>Resources\ParentingEducation\Worksheet\docs\Scale I.pdf</location>
			<url>P:\225 evenstart\working\2011 Meeting Materials\Tribal\Scale I.pdf</url>
			<top_level_id>PE</top_level_id>
			<second_level_id>W</second_level_id>
			<tag></tag>
			<desc>This document provides a 5-level scale for rating how well parents support their children's literacy education at home.</desc>
			<synopsis>There are 4 areas that parents are rated in on this 5 point scale. The 3 areas are: use of literacy materials; use of electronic media; home language and learning; and priority on learning together. A description for what a parent at each rating level typically does is given. The second page provides space to rate a parent in each area and to give a rationale for the rating.</synopsis>
			<synopsis_cont></synopsis_cont>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Scale for Rating Parent's Role in Interactive Literacy Activities</name>
			<file_type>PDF</file_type>
			<location>Resources\ParentingEducation\Worksheet\docs\Scale II.pdf</location>
			<url>P:\225 evenstart\working\2011 Meeting Materials\Tribal\Scale II.pdf</url>
			<top_level_id>PE</top_level_id>
			<second_level_id>W</second_level_id>
			<tag></tag>
			<desc>This document provides a 5-level scale for rating how productively parents engage in interactive literacy activities with their children.</desc>
			<synopsis>There are 3 areas that parents are rated in on this 5 point scale. The 3 areas are: expressive and receptive language use; reading with children; and supporting book and print concepts. A description for what a parent at each rating level typically does is given. The second page provides space to rate a parent in each area and to give a rationale for the rating.</synopsis>
			<synopsis_cont></synopsis_cont>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Scale for Rating Parent's Role in Supporting Child's Learning in Formal Education Settings</name>
			<file_type>PDF</file_type>
			<location>Resources\ParentingEducation\Worksheet\docs\Scale III.pdf</location>
			<url>P:\225 evenstart\working\2011 Meeting Materials\Tribal\Scale III.pdf</url>
			<top_level_id>PE</top_level_id>
			<second_level_id>W</second_level_id>
			<tag></tag>
			<desc>This document provides a 5-level scale for rating how well parents support their children's learning in formal education settings.</desc>
			<synopsis>There are 5 areas that parents are rated in on this 5 point scale. The 5 areas are: parent-school communications; expectations of child and family; monitoring progress and reinforcing learning; partnership with educational settings; and belief in child's success in learning. A description for what a parent at each rating level typically does is given. The second page provides space to rate a parent in each area and to give a rationale for the rating.</synopsis>
			<synopsis_cont></synopsis_cont>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Scale for Rating Taking on the Parent Role</name>
			<file_type>PDF</file_type>
			<location>Resources\ParentingEducation\Worksheet\docs\Scale IV.pdf</location>
			<url>P:\225 evenstart\working\2011 Meeting Materials\Tribal\Scale IV.pdf</url>
			<top_level_id>PE</top_level_id>
			<second_level_id>W</second_level_id>
			<tag></tag>
			<desc>This document provides a 5-level scale for rating how successfully parents take on the role of parenting.</desc>
			<synopsis>There are 3 areas that parents are rated in on this 5 point scale. The 3 areas are: managing stress on children; safety and health of children; and choices, rules, and limits. A description for what a parent at each rating level typically does is given. The second page provides space to rate a parent in each area and to give a rationale for the rating.</synopsis>
			<synopsis_cont></synopsis_cont>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Scale for Parent's Role in Interactive Literacy Activities: Expressive and Receptive Language</name>
			<file_type>PDF</file_type>
			<location>Resources\ParentingEducation\Guidelines\docs\Responses IIE revised.pdf</location>
			<url>P:\225 evenstart\working\2011 Meeting Materials\Tribal\Responses IIE revised.pdf</url>
			<top_level_id>PE</top_level_id>
			<second_level_id>G</second_level_id>
			<tag></tag>
			<desc>This chart gives suggestions for instructors to help parents improve in their use of expressive and receptive language in interactive literacy activities.</desc>
			<synopsis>This chart breaks down the scale for interactive literacy activities. It uses another 5 point scale to rate how parents use expressive and receptive language. It describes what a parent at each level looks like, and gives suggestions on how to model positive behaviors for the parents to follow.</synopsis>
			<synopsis_cont></synopsis_cont>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Scale for Parent's Role in Interactive Literacy Activities: Supporting Book/Print Concepts</name>
			<file_type>PDF</file_type>
			<location>Resources\ParentingEducation\Guidelines\docs\Responses IIG revised.pdf</location>
			<url>P:\225 evenstart\working\2011 Meeting Materials\Tribal\Responses IIG revised.pdf</url>
			<top_level_id>PE</top_level_id>
			<second_level_id>G</second_level_id>
			<tag></tag>
			<desc>This chart gives suggestions for instructors to help parents support the development of book and print concepts in their child's learning.</desc>
			<synopsis>This chart breaks down the scale for interactive literacy activities. It uses another 5 point scale to rate how parents support book and print concepts in their child's learning. It describes what a parent at each level looks like, and gives suggestions on how to model positive behaviors for the parents to follow.</synopsis>
			<synopsis_cont></synopsis_cont>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Scale for Parent's Role in Interactive Literacy Activities: Reading with Children</name>
			<file_type>PDF</file_type>
			<location>Resources\ParentingEducation\Guidelines\docs\Responses Scale IIF.pdf</location>
			<url>P:\225 evenstart\working\2011 Meeting Materials\Tribal\Responses Scale IIF.pdf</url>
			<top_level_id>PE</top_level_id>
			<second_level_id>G</second_level_id>
			<tag></tag>
			<desc>This chart gives suggestions for instructors to help parents read productively with their children.</desc>
			<synopsis>This chart breaks down the scale for interactive literacy activities. It uses another 5 point scale to rate how productively parents read with their children. It describes what a parent at each level looks like, and gives suggestions on how to model positive behaviors for the parents to follow.</synopsis>
			<synopsis_cont></synopsis_cont>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Meaningful Differences in the Everyday Experience of Young American Children</name>
			<file_type>PDF</file_type>
			<location>Resources\ParentingEducation\Research\docs\T  Risley - Meaningful Differences.pdf</location>
			<url>P:\225 evenstart\working\2011 Meeting Materials\Tribal\T Risley - Meaningful Differences.pdf</url>
			<top_level_id>PE</top_level_id>
			<second_level_id>R</second_level_id>
			<tag>Todd Risley, Betty Hart, achievement gap</tag>
			<desc>This document summarizes the results of a long-term study on differences in language use in families and how that impacts children's language acquisition.</desc>
			<synopsis>The study summarized here showed that low-income parents tend to talk less to their children and when they do talk, that they use less complex language. It also showed that early language experiences and vocabulary exposure in the family can affect a child's later academic success.</synopsis>
			<synopsis_cont></synopsis_cont>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Teaching Parents New Skills to Support Their Children's Development</name>
			<file_type>PDF</file_type>
			<location>Resources\ParentingEducation\Research\docs\Teaching Parents New Skills_handout.pdf</location>
			<url>P:\225 evenstart\working\2011 Meeting Materials\Tribal\Teaching Parents New Skills_handout.pdf</url>
			<top_level_id>PE</top_level_id>
			<second_level_id>R</second_level_id>
			<tag>Ann P. Kaiser, Terry B. Hancock, special education</tag>
			<desc>This article outlines skills parent educators need to be able to teach parents new skills to support the learning of their young children with developmental
disabilities.
			</desc>
			<synopsis>This article proposes that teaching parents to
implement family-centered interventions can be highly effective by: (a) allowing parents to choose
when to learn new skills; (b) teaching parents strategies that are empirically based, well-matched to their child&#x2019;s developmental needs, and intended to be implemented in naturally occurring interactions between parents and children; and (c) teaching parents in a skillful and individualized manner. The article discusses a research-based model for preparing professionals to teach parents.
			</synopsis>
			<synopsis_cont></synopsis_cont>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Using Ipods to Supplement and Enhance ESL Instruction for Even Start Parents</name>
			<file_type>PDF</file_type>
			<location>Resources\AdultEducation\Research\docs\IPod for ESL_New York.pdf</location>
			<url>http://www.evenstartnetwork.net/_version2b/assets/doc/BusinessMeetings/2011/IPod%20for%20ESL_New%20York.pdf</url>
			<top_level_id>AE</top_level_id>
			<second_level_id>R</second_level_id>
			<tag>ESL, ELL, New York</tag>
			<desc>This document describes a family literacy program's venture to use iPods to supplement adult ESL instruction.</desc>
			<synopsis>For this venture the family literacy program purchased 10 iPods and loaded them with audio components to supplement the curriculum.  Each ELL adult's language ability was assessed so that the audio could be customized to meet each learner's needs. The article goes on to summarize the benefits and drawbacks of iPod use, and lessons learned from the venture.</synopsis>
			<synopsis_cont></synopsis_cont>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Long Term Outcomes of Texas Even Start Participants</name>
			<file_type>PDF</file_type>
			<location>Resources\AdultEducation\Research\docs\Long Term Outcomes of ES Participants_Texas.pdf</location>
			<url>http://www.evenstartnetwork.net/_version2b/assets/doc/BusinessMeetings/2011/Long%20Term%20Outcomes%20of%20ES%20Participants_Texas.pdf</url>
			<top_level_id>AE, ECE</top_level_id>
			<second_level_id>R</second_level_id>
			<tag>Texas, Elizabeth B. Thompson</tag>
			<desc>This presentation summarizes outcomes for both adults and childrens who have participated in Even Start family literacy programs in Texas.</desc>
			<synopsis>This presentation shows increased outcomes in terms of employability and academic success for both adults and children who have participated in Even Start. For the child portion of the study, there was also a control group that was not enrolled in Even Start. The parents were also surveyed about how they and their children were doing after participating in the program. Data on all of these topics are presented.</synopsis>
			<synopsis_cont></synopsis_cont>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Long Range Outcomes of Even Start Program on Participating Parents</name>
			<file_type>PDF</file_type>
			<location>Resources\AdultEducation\Research\docs\Long Range Outcomes_Texas Handouts.pdf</location>
			<url>http://www.evenstartnetwork.net/_version2b/assets/doc/BusinessMeetings/2011/Long%20Range%20Outcomes_Texas%20Handouts.pdf</url>
			<top_level_id>AE, ECE</top_level_id>
			<second_level_id>R</second_level_id>
			<tag>Texas, Elizabeth B. Thompson, Don Seaman, Chia-Yin Chen</tag>
			<desc>This document presents key points from a study measuring outcomes for adults and children who participated in Even Start family literacy programs in Texas.</desc>
			<synopsis>This document describes both the parent and child sections of the study. Topics highlighted include study design, demographics of the population studied, results, and conclusions. Graphs of trends are included along with lists of state and national factors that came into effect during the course of the study and may have influenced the results. Overall the study found increased employability and academic success for participants.</synopsis>
			<synopsis_cont></synopsis_cont>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Guide to Quality: Even Start Family Literacy Program Implementation and Continuous Improvement Volume 1, Revised</name>
			<file_type>PDF</file_type>
			<location>Resources\ParentingEducation\Guidelines\docs\ES_GuideToQuality(April62010).pdf</location>
			<url>http://www.evenstartnetwork.net/_version2b/assets/doc/pdf/ES_GuideToQuality%28April62010%29.pdf</url>
			<top_level_id>PE</top_level_id>
			<second_level_id>G</second_level_id>
			<tag>guide to quality, quality guide</tag>
			<desc>This guide describes characteristics of high quality, effective Even Start programs and was developed as a tool for continuous program improvement.</desc>
			<synopsis>The Guide to Quality is broken into several topic areas with a statement of the primary goal, including partnerships and collaboration, staff development, the four core instructional components, and transitions. Then a series of quality considerations are listed for each topic. These are considerations associated with high quality programs based on evaluation, research, theory, best practices, and legal requirements. The quality considerations and then followed by "signs of problems" in each area. These are intended to be red flags and may be used to prompt discussion and/or facilitate action.</synopsis>
			<synopsis_cont></synopsis_cont>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Guide to Local Evaluations of Even Start Family Literacy Programs:</name>
			<file_type>PDF</file_type>
			<location>Resources\ParentingEducation\Guidelines\docs\guide_local_eval_esflp_March52010.pdf</location>
			<url>http://www.evenstartnetwork.net/_version2b/assets/doc/pdf/guide_local_eval_esflp_March52010.pdf</url>
			<top_level_id>PE</top_level_id>
			<second_level_id>G</second_level_id>
			<tag>local evaluation, evaluation</tag>
			<desc>This guide provides a framework for planning and developing a high quality Even Start family literacy program evaluation.</desc>
			<synopsis>The Guide to Local Evaluations is a resource for program directors and evaluators to help in the planning and design of an evaluation. The guide is broken up into 12 chapters that address the components of the evaluation framework (Participant Learning Outcomes, Participation, Learning Milestones, Program Design, and Program Implementation), address how to organize information from multiple data sources, and other issues including how to select and work with an evaluator and how to develop agreements and plans.</synopsis>
			<synopsis_cont></synopsis_cont>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Guide to Parenting Education in Even Start Family Literacy Programs</name>
			<file_type>PDF</file_type>
			<location>Resources\ParentingEducation\Guidelines\docs\Parenting Education.pdf</location>
			<url>http://www.evenstartnetwork.net/_version2b/assets/doc/pdf/Parenting%20Education.pdf</url>
			<top_level_id>PE</top_level_id>
			<second_level_id>G</second_level_id>
			<tag>Diane D'Angelo, Douglas Powell, parenting</tag>
			<desc>The Guide to Improving Parenting Education in Even Start Family Literacy Programs provides a framework to strengthen the quality and impact of parent education programs.</desc>
			<synopsis>The Guide to Improving Parenting Education Programs in Family Literacy Programs is based on a review of research literature on family contributions to children's literacy development, structured visits to local Even Start programs, extensive consultation with professionals associated with family literacy programs, and constructive feedback from state coordinators and staff. The Guide outlines five goal areas for parenting education; providing the research-based behind each goal area and provides ideas for putting the framework into action.</synopsis>
			<synopsis_cont></synopsis_cont>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Doing What Works</name>
<!--			<file_type>link</file_type>-->
			<file_type>URL</file_type>
			<location>http://dww.ed.gov/Preschool-Language-and-Literacy/topic/?T_ID=15</location>
			<url>http://dww.ed.gov/Preschool-Language-and-Literacy/topic/?T_ID=15</url>
			<top_level_id>ECE</top_level_id>
			<second_level_id>G, R</second_level_id>
			<tag>practices</tag>
			<desc>This website provides practical, research-based practices for preschool practioners.</desc>
			<synopsis>Preschool education is important to a child's long-term success. this website provides practical information about two research-based practices to improve instruction in foundational pre-reading skills and provides suggestions for how the website can be used to support and train teachers in learning these practices to improve the quality of preschool instruction.</synopsis>
			<synopsis_cont></synopsis_cont>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Making Meaningful Changes in Program Design - Practice and Play</name>
			<file_type>PDF</file_type>
			<location>Resources\EarlyChildhoodEducation\TeachingActivity\docs\Module 3.pdf</location>
			<url>http://www.evenstartnetwork.net/pdf/Module%203.pdf</url>
			<top_level_id>ECE</top_level_id>
			<second_level_id>TA</second_level_id>
			<tag>program design, practice, play</tag>
			<desc>Presentation slides on practice and play</desc>
			<synopsis>Presentation slides for module on practice and play for ECE program design training</synopsis>
			<synopsis_cont></synopsis_cont>
		</item>
	</assets>
</root>
